[
    {
        "Question": "Do people with an autism spectrum disorder always suffer from intellectual disability?",
        "Answer": "It is estimated that around 50% of persons with ASD also suffer from an intellectual disability.\nSome individuals with ASD have an intellectual disability whilst some have average or above average intelligence.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.who.int/news-room/q-a-detail/autism-spectrum-disorders-(asd)\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are the causes of Autism Spectrum Disorders (ASDs)?",
        "Answer": "The cause is unknown at present. Scientific evidence suggests that genetic, biological and environmental factors contribute to the onset of ASD by influencing early brain development. \nSome risk factors for ASD include:\n1. Having a sibling with ASD.\n2. Having older parents.\n3. Having certain genetic conditions: people with conditions such as Down syndrome, fragile X syndrome, and Rett syndrome are more likely than others to have ASD.\nRead more:\nhttps://rockmelon.com/about-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What causes autism spectrum disorder (also known as ASD)?",
        "Answer": "The cause is unknown at present. Scientific evidence suggests that genetic, biological and environmental factors contribute to the onset of ASD by influencing early brain development. \nSome risk factors for ASD include:\n1. Having a sibling with ASD.\n2. Having older parents.\n3. Having certain genetic conditions: people with conditions such as Down syndrome, fragile X syndrome, and Rett syndrome are more likely than others to have ASD.\nRead more:\nhttps://rockmelon.com/about-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What causes autism?",
        "Answer": "The cause is unknown at present. Scientific evidence suggests that genetic, biological and environmental factors contribute to the onset of ASD by influencing early brain development. \nSome risk factors for ASD include:\n1. Having a sibling with ASD.\n2. Having older parents.\n3. Having certain genetic conditions: people with conditions such as Down syndrome, fragile X syndrome, and Rett syndrome are more likely than others to have ASD.\nRead more:\nhttps://rockmelon.com/about-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What causes autism? Can it be cured?",
        "Answer": "The cause is unknown at present. Scientific evidence suggests that genetic, biological and environmental factors contribute to the onset of ASD by influencing early brain development. \nSome risk factors for ASD include:\n1. Having a sibling with ASD.\n2. Having older parents.\n3. Having certain genetic conditions: people with conditions such as Down syndrome, fragile X syndrome, and Rett syndrome are more likely than others to have ASD.\nRead more:\nhttps://rockmelon.com/about-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Did I Cause My Child's Autism?",
        "Answer": "The cause is unknown at present. Scientific evidence suggests that genetic, biological and environmental factors contribute to the onset of ASD by influencing early brain development. \nSome risk factors for ASD include:\n1. Having a sibling with ASD.\n2. Having older parents.\n3. Having certain genetic conditions: people with conditions such as Down syndrome, fragile X syndrome, and Rett syndrome are more likely than others to have ASD.\nRead more:\nhttps://rockmelon.com/about-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are the causes and/or risk factors for ASD?",
        "Answer": "The cause is unknown at present. Scientific evidence suggests that genetic, biological and environmental factors contribute to the onset of ASD by influencing early brain development. \nSome risk factors for ASD include:\n1. Having a sibling with ASD.\n2. Having older parents.\n3. Having certain genetic conditions: people with conditions such as Down syndrome, fragile X syndrome, and Rett syndrome are more likely than others to have ASD.\nRead more:\nhttps://rockmelon.com/about-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Are there risk factors for Autism?",
        "Answer": "The cause is unknown at present. Scientific evidence suggests that genetic, biological and environmental factors contribute to the onset of ASD by influencing early brain development. \nSome risk factors for ASD include:\n1. Having a sibling with ASD.\n2. Having older parents.\n3. Having certain genetic conditions: people with conditions such as Down syndrome, fragile X syndrome, and Rett syndrome are more likely than others to have ASD.\nRead more:\nhttps://rockmelon.com/about-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Is Autism is almost always genetic?",
        "Answer": "The cause is unknown at present. Scientific evidence suggests that genetic, biological and environmental factors contribute to the onset of ASD by influencing early brain development. \nSome risk factors for ASD include:\n1. Having a sibling with ASD.\n2. Having older parents.\n3. Having certain genetic conditions: people with conditions such as Down syndrome, fragile X syndrome, and Rett syndrome are more likely than others to have ASD.\nRead more:\nhttps://rockmelon.com/about-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How can I find out what caused my child's autism?",
        "Answer": "The cause is unknown at present. Scientific evidence suggests that genetic, biological and environmental factors contribute to the onset of ASD by influencing early brain development. \nSome risk factors for ASD include:\n1. Having a sibling with ASD.\n2. Having older parents.\n3. Having certain genetic conditions: people with conditions such as Down syndrome, fragile X syndrome, and Rett syndrome are more likely than others to have ASD.\nRead more:\nhttps://rockmelon.com/about-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Why My Child Has Autism?",
        "Answer": "The cause is unknown at present. Scientific evidence suggests that genetic, biological and environmental factors contribute to the onset of ASD by influencing early brain development. \nSome risk factors for ASD include:\n1. Having a sibling with ASD.\n2. Having older parents.\n3. Having certain genetic conditions: people with conditions such as Down syndrome, fragile X syndrome, and Rett syndrome are more likely than others to have ASD.\nRead more:\nhttps://rockmelon.com/about-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are the signs and symptoms of Autism?",
        "Answer": "Identifying ASD is difficult before the age of about 12 months but is generally possible by the age of 2 years. Symptoms of ASD vary from child to child. The DSM-5, the standard reference used by most healthcare providers, includes a full list of autism diagnostic criteria.\nCommon early signs include:  \n1. Delayed speech or difficulty communicating. \n2. Poor eye contact. \n3. Little or no imaginative play. \n4. No joint attention, not looking in the same direction as others. \n5. Showing limited interest in other people. \n6. Highly emotional responses to changes in routine.  \nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/is-it-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are 16 early signs of autism by 16 months?",
        "Answer": "Identifying ASD is difficult before the age of about 12 months but is generally possible by the age of 2 years. Symptoms of ASD vary from child to child. The DSM-5, the standard reference used by most healthcare providers, includes a full list of autism diagnostic criteria.\nCommon early signs include:  \n1. Delayed speech or difficulty communicating. \n2. Poor eye contact. \n3. Little or no imaginative play. \n4. No joint attention, not looking in the same direction as others. \n5. Showing limited interest in other people. \n6. Highly emotional responses to changes in routine.  \nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/is-it-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are early red flags of ASD in toddlers?",
        "Answer": "Identifying ASD is difficult before the age of about 12 months but is generally possible by the age of 2 years. Symptoms of ASD vary from child to child. The DSM-5, the standard reference used by most healthcare providers, includes a full list of autism diagnostic criteria.\nCommon early signs include:  \n1. Delayed speech or difficulty communicating. \n2. Poor eye contact. \n3. Little or no imaginative play. \n4. No joint attention, not looking in the same direction as others. \n5. Showing limited interest in other people. \n6. Highly emotional responses to changes in routine.  \nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/is-it-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are the early signs of autism?",
        "Answer": "Identifying ASD is difficult before the age of about 12 months but is generally possible by the age of 2 years. Symptoms of ASD vary from child to child. The DSM-5, the standard reference used by most healthcare providers, includes a full list of autism diagnostic criteria.\nCommon early signs include:  \n1. Delayed speech or difficulty communicating. \n2. Poor eye contact. \n3. Little or no imaginative play. \n4. No joint attention, not looking in the same direction as others. \n5. Showing limited interest in other people. \n6. Highly emotional responses to changes in routine.  \nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/is-it-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are the most common signs of autism?",
        "Answer": "Identifying ASD is difficult before the age of about 12 months but is generally possible by the age of 2 years. Symptoms of ASD vary from child to child. The DSM-5, the standard reference used by most healthcare providers, includes a full list of autism diagnostic criteria.\nCommon early signs include:  \n1. Delayed speech or difficulty communicating. \n2. Poor eye contact. \n3. Little or no imaginative play. \n4. No joint attention, not looking in the same direction as others. \n5. Showing limited interest in other people. \n6. Highly emotional responses to changes in routine.  \nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/is-it-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What age do children usually start to show signs of autism?",
        "Answer": "Identifying ASD is difficult before the age of about 12 months but is generally possible by the age of 2 years. Symptoms of ASD vary from child to child. The DSM-5, the standard reference used by most healthcare providers, includes a full list of autism diagnostic criteria.\nCommon early signs include:  \n1. Delayed speech or difficulty communicating. \n2. Poor eye contact. \n3. Little or no imaginative play. \n4. No joint attention, not looking in the same direction as others. \n5. Showing limited interest in other people. \n6. Highly emotional responses to changes in routine.  \nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/is-it-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How old do children usually start to show signs of autism?",
        "Answer": "Identifying ASD is difficult before the age of about 12 months but is generally possible by the age of 2 years. Symptoms of ASD vary from child to child. The DSM-5, the standard reference used by most healthcare providers, includes a full list of autism diagnostic criteria.\nCommon early signs include:  \n1. Delayed speech or difficulty communicating. \n2. Poor eye contact. \n3. Little or no imaginative play. \n4. No joint attention, not looking in the same direction as others. \n5. Showing limited interest in other people. \n6. Highly emotional responses to changes in routine.  \nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/is-it-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "When do signs or symptoms of autism appear?",
        "Answer": "Identifying ASD is difficult before the age of about 12 months but is generally possible by the age of 2 years. Symptoms of ASD vary from child to child. The DSM-5, the standard reference used by most healthcare providers, includes a full list of autism diagnostic criteria.\nCommon early signs include:  \n1. Delayed speech or difficulty communicating. \n2. Poor eye contact. \n3. Little or no imaginative play. \n4. No joint attention, not looking in the same direction as others. \n5. Showing limited interest in other people. \n6. Highly emotional responses to changes in routine.  \nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/is-it-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How early can an autism spectrum disorder be recognized in children?",
        "Answer": "Identifying ASD is difficult before the age of about 12 months but is generally possible by the age of 2 years. Symptoms of ASD vary from child to child. The DSM-5, the standard reference used by most healthcare providers, includes a full list of autism diagnostic criteria.\nCommon early signs include:  \n1. Delayed speech or difficulty communicating. \n2. Poor eye contact. \n3. Little or no imaginative play. \n4. No joint attention, not looking in the same direction as others. \n5. Showing limited interest in other people. \n6. Highly emotional responses to changes in routine.  \nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/is-it-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is Autism Spectrum Disorder (ASD) in Children",
        "Answer": "Identifying ASD is difficult before the age of about 12 months but is generally possible by the age of 2 years. Symptoms of ASD vary from child to child. The DSM-5, the standard reference used by most healthcare providers, includes a full list of autism diagnostic criteria.\nCommon early signs include:  \n1. Delayed speech or difficulty communicating. \n2. Poor eye contact. \n3. Little or no imaginative play. \n4. No joint attention, not looking in the same direction as others. \n5. Showing limited interest in other people. \n6. Highly emotional responses to changes in routine.  \nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/is-it-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How do doctors diagnose children with Autism?",
        "Answer": "Identifying ASD is difficult before the age of about 12 months but is generally possible by the age of 2 years. Symptoms of ASD vary from child to child. The DSM-5, the standard reference used by most healthcare providers, includes a full list of autism diagnostic criteria.\nCommon early signs include:  \n1. Delayed speech or difficulty communicating. \n2. Poor eye contact. \n3. Little or no imaginative play. \n4. No joint attention, not looking in the same direction as others. \n5. Showing limited interest in other people. \n6. Highly emotional responses to changes in routine.  \nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/is-it-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "My child is 3 and not talking yet, does this mean he has autism?",
        "Answer": "Identifying ASD is difficult before the age of about 12 months but is generally possible by the age of 2 years. Symptoms of ASD vary from child to child. The DSM-5, the standard reference used by most healthcare providers, includes a full list of autism diagnostic criteria.\nCommon early signs include:  \n1. Delayed speech or difficulty communicating. \n2. Poor eye contact. \n3. Little or no imaginative play. \n4. No joint attention, not looking in the same direction as others. \n5. Showing limited interest in other people. \n6. Highly emotional responses to changes in routine.  \nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/is-it-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Are symptoms of autism usually the same in every child",
        "Answer": "Identifying ASD is difficult before the age of about 12 months but is generally possible by the age of 2 years. Symptoms of ASD vary from child to child. The DSM-5, the standard reference used by most healthcare providers, includes a full list of autism diagnostic criteria.\nCommon early signs include:  \n1. Delayed speech or difficulty communicating. \n2. Poor eye contact. \n3. Little or no imaginative play. \n4. No joint attention, not looking in the same direction as others. \n5. Showing limited interest in other people. \n6. Highly emotional responses to changes in routine.  \nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/is-it-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are some of the behaviors exhibited by a child who may have an autism spectrum disorder?",
        "Answer": "Identifying ASD is difficult before the age of about 12 months but is generally possible by the age of 2 years. Symptoms of ASD vary from child to child. The DSM-5, the standard reference used by most healthcare providers, includes a full list of autism diagnostic criteria.\nCommon early signs include:  \n1. Delayed speech or difficulty communicating. \n2. Poor eye contact. \n3. Little or no imaginative play. \n4. No joint attention, not looking in the same direction as others. \n5. Showing limited interest in other people. \n6. Highly emotional responses to changes in routine.  \nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/is-it-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are some of the common myths about autism?",
        "Answer": "1. Individuals on the autism spectrum avoid social contact.\n2. Individuals on the autism spectrum cannot lead independent and successful lives\n3. Autism is the result of bad parenting.\n4. All individuals on the autism spectrum have special talent or 'savant' skills.\n5. Autism can be cured.\n6. People with autism do not make eye contact.\n7. People with autism cannot talk.\n8. Autism can be outgrown.\n9. Individuals on the autism spectrum do not have feelings and thus are unable to show affection.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org.sg/living-with-autism/myths-and-facts-of-autism\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Who should I tell about the diagnosis?",
        "Answer": "Any professional involved with the adult should know that they have been diagnosed with an ASD. Sometimes, if the person is mildly affected by ASD or Asperger Syndrome, it may not be necessary to tell others. Usually, however, telling people helps them understand the person better and interact more effectively with them.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autismontario.com/sites/default/files/2020-04/Getting%20a%20Diagnosis%20of%20ASD_0.pdf\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What progress has been made so far in autism research?",
        "Answer": "Autism research is quickly developing across many areas, including genetics, neurobiology, educational interventions, and targeted medications. One promising area of research seeks to identify autism genes in order to develop new medications based on genetic findings.\nRead more:\nhttps://icahn.mssm.edu/research/seaver/resources/autism-faqs\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What research is being done on austism?",
        "Answer": "Autism research is quickly developing across many areas, including genetics, neurobiology, educational interventions, and targeted medications. One promising area of research seeks to identify autism genes in order to develop new medications based on genetic findings.\nRead more:\nhttps://icahn.mssm.edu/research/seaver/resources/autism-faqs\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How common is ASD?",
        "Answer": "According to recent estimates released by Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC): \n1. Approximately 1 in 54 children in the U.S. is diagnosed with an autism spectrum disorder (ASD).\n2. 1 in 34 boys identified with autism.\n3. 1 in 144 girls identified with autism.\n4. Boys are 4 times more likely to be diagnosed with autism than girls.\nEstimates of autism prevalence have risen steadily since the CDC began tracking the condition. What appears to be rising rates are largely due to changing definitions of autism along with expanded screenings.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.myautismteam.com/resources/autism-an-overview\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is the prevalance of ASD?",
        "Answer": "According to recent estimates released by Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC): \n1. Approximately 1 in 54 children in the U.S. is diagnosed with an autism spectrum disorder (ASD).\n2. 1 in 34 boys identified with autism.\n3. 1 in 144 girls identified with autism.\n4. Boys are 4 times more likely to be diagnosed with autism than girls.\nEstimates of autism prevalence have risen steadily since the CDC began tracking the condition. What appears to be rising rates are largely due to changing definitions of autism along with expanded screenings.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.myautismteam.com/resources/autism-an-overview\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Is autism a condition that affects only males?",
        "Answer": "According to recent estimates released by Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC): \n1. Approximately 1 in 54 children in the U.S. is diagnosed with an autism spectrum disorder (ASD).\n2. 1 in 34 boys identified with autism.\n3. 1 in 144 girls identified with autism.\n4. Boys are 4 times more likely to be diagnosed with autism than girls.\nEstimates of autism prevalence have risen steadily since the CDC began tracking the condition. What appears to be rising rates are largely due to changing definitions of autism along with expanded screenings.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.myautismteam.com/resources/autism-an-overview\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Who Develops ASD?",
        "Answer": "According to recent estimates released by Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC): \n1. Approximately 1 in 54 children in the U.S. is diagnosed with an autism spectrum disorder (ASD).\n2. 1 in 34 boys identified with autism.\n3. 1 in 144 girls identified with autism.\n4. Boys are 4 times more likely to be diagnosed with autism than girls.\nEstimates of autism prevalence have risen steadily since the CDC began tracking the condition. What appears to be rising rates are largely due to changing definitions of autism along with expanded screenings.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.myautismteam.com/resources/autism-an-overview\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Are boys more likely to develop austism than girls?",
        "Answer": "According to recent estimates released by Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC): \n1. Approximately 1 in 54 children in the U.S. is diagnosed with an autism spectrum disorder (ASD).\n2. 1 in 34 boys identified with autism.\n3. 1 in 144 girls identified with autism.\n4. Boys are 4 times more likely to be diagnosed with autism than girls.\nEstimates of autism prevalence have risen steadily since the CDC began tracking the condition. What appears to be rising rates are largely due to changing definitions of autism along with expanded screenings.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.myautismteam.com/resources/autism-an-overview\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Are girls more likely to develop austism than boys?",
        "Answer": "According to recent estimates released by Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC): \n1. Approximately 1 in 54 children in the U.S. is diagnosed with an autism spectrum disorder (ASD).\n2. 1 in 34 boys identified with autism.\n3. 1 in 144 girls identified with autism.\n4. Boys are 4 times more likely to be diagnosed with autism than girls.\nEstimates of autism prevalence have risen steadily since the CDC began tracking the condition. What appears to be rising rates are largely due to changing definitions of autism along with expanded screenings.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.myautismteam.com/resources/autism-an-overview\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Who among boys and girls is more likely to develop autism?",
        "Answer": "According to recent estimates released by Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC): \n1. Approximately 1 in 54 children in the U.S. is diagnosed with an autism spectrum disorder (ASD).\n2. 1 in 34 boys identified with autism.\n3. 1 in 144 girls identified with autism.\n4. Boys are 4 times more likely to be diagnosed with autism than girls.\nEstimates of autism prevalence have risen steadily since the CDC began tracking the condition. What appears to be rising rates are largely due to changing definitions of autism along with expanded screenings.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.myautismteam.com/resources/autism-an-overview\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Are boys or girls more likely to develop autism?",
        "Answer": "According to recent estimates released by Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC): \n1. Approximately 1 in 54 children in the U.S. is diagnosed with an autism spectrum disorder (ASD).\n2. 1 in 34 boys identified with autism.\n3. 1 in 144 girls identified with autism.\n4. Boys are 4 times more likely to be diagnosed with autism than girls.\nEstimates of autism prevalence have risen steadily since the CDC began tracking the condition. What appears to be rising rates are largely due to changing definitions of autism along with expanded screenings.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.myautismteam.com/resources/autism-an-overview\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Are rates of autism increasing?",
        "Answer": "According to recent estimates released by Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC): \n1. Approximately 1 in 54 children in the U.S. is diagnosed with an autism spectrum disorder (ASD).\n2. 1 in 34 boys identified with autism.\n3. 1 in 144 girls identified with autism.\n4. Boys are 4 times more likely to be diagnosed with autism than girls.\nEstimates of autism prevalence have risen steadily since the CDC began tracking the condition. What appears to be rising rates are largely due to changing definitions of autism along with expanded screenings.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.myautismteam.com/resources/autism-an-overview\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How common are autism spectrum disorders?",
        "Answer": "According to recent estimates released by Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC): \n1. Approximately 1 in 54 children in the U.S. is diagnosed with an autism spectrum disorder (ASD).\n2. 1 in 34 boys identified with autism.\n3. 1 in 144 girls identified with autism.\n4. Boys are 4 times more likely to be diagnosed with autism than girls.\nEstimates of autism prevalence have risen steadily since the CDC began tracking the condition. What appears to be rising rates are largely due to changing definitions of autism along with expanded screenings.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.myautismteam.com/resources/autism-an-overview\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How common is ASD?",
        "Answer": "According to recent estimates released by Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC): \n1. Approximately 1 in 54 children in the U.S. is diagnosed with an autism spectrum disorder (ASD).\n2. 1 in 34 boys identified with autism.\n3. 1 in 144 girls identified with autism.\n4. Boys are 4 times more likely to be diagnosed with autism than girls.\nEstimates of autism prevalence have risen steadily since the CDC began tracking the condition. What appears to be rising rates are largely due to changing definitions of autism along with expanded screenings.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.myautismteam.com/resources/autism-an-overview\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How common is autism?",
        "Answer": "According to recent estimates released by Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC): \n1. Approximately 1 in 54 children in the U.S. is diagnosed with an autism spectrum disorder (ASD).\n2. 1 in 34 boys identified with autism.\n3. 1 in 144 girls identified with autism.\n4. Boys are 4 times more likely to be diagnosed with autism than girls.\nEstimates of autism prevalence have risen steadily since the CDC began tracking the condition. What appears to be rising rates are largely due to changing definitions of autism along with expanded screenings.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.myautismteam.com/resources/autism-an-overview\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How many people have autism?",
        "Answer": "According to recent estimates released by Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC): \n1. Approximately 1 in 54 children in the U.S. is diagnosed with an autism spectrum disorder (ASD).\n2. 1 in 34 boys identified with autism.\n3. 1 in 144 girls identified with autism.\n4. Boys are 4 times more likely to be diagnosed with autism than girls.\nEstimates of autism prevalence have risen steadily since the CDC began tracking the condition. What appears to be rising rates are largely due to changing definitions of autism along with expanded screenings.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.myautismteam.com/resources/autism-an-overview\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is regressive encephalopathy?",
        "Answer": "Encephalopathy is a medical term for a disease or disorder of the brain. It usually means a slowing down of brain function. Regressive Encephalopathy means there is a disease or disorder in the brain that makes a person lose skills they once had. We know that sometimes children with mitochondrial diseases seem to be developing as they should, but around toddler or preschool age, they regress. This could be something like malnutrition, an illness such as flu, a high fever, dehydration, or it could be something else.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.cdc.gov/ncbddd/autism/topics.html\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Do symptoms of autism change over time?",
        "Answer": "For many children, symptoms improve with age and behavioral treatment. \nDuring adolescence, some children with ASD may become depressed or experience behavioral problems, and their treatment may need some modification as they transition to adulthood. People with ASD usually continue to need services and supports as they get older, but depending on severity of the disorder, people with ASD may be able to work successfully and live independently or within a supportive environment.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.ninds.nih.gov/Disorders/Patient-Caregiver-Education/Fact-Sheets/Autism-Spectrum-Disorder-Fact-Sheet#3082_5\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Speech Development in ASD?",
        "Answer": "An analysis of ARI's (Autism Research Institute) data involving 30,145 cases indicated that 9% never develop speech. Of those 91% who develop speech, 43% begin to talk by the end of their first year, 35% begin to talk sometime between their first and second year, and 22% begin to talk in their third year and after. With appropriate interventions, there is reason to hope that children with autism can learn to talk, at least to some extent, and non-verbal older children and adults can sometimes learn to talk or communicate in other ways.\nRead More: \nhttps://www.autism.org/advice-for-parents/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Will my autistic child develop speech? ",
        "Answer": "An analysis of ARI's (Autism Research Institute) data involving 30,145 cases indicated that 9% never develop speech. Of those 91% who develop speech, 43% begin to talk by the end of their first year, 35% begin to talk sometime between their first and second year, and 22% begin to talk in their third year and after. With appropriate interventions, there is reason to hope that children with autism can learn to talk, at least to some extent, and non-verbal older children and adults can sometimes learn to talk or communicate in other ways.\nRead More: \nhttps://www.autism.org/advice-for-parents/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are the different names and terms for autism?",
        "Answer": "Over the years, different diagnostic labels have been used, such as: autism, Autism Spectrum Disorder (ASD), Autism Spectrum Condition (ASC), classic autism, Kanner autism, pervasive developmental disorder (PDD), high-functioning autism (HFA), Asperger syndrome and Pathological Demand Avoidance (PDA). This reflects the different diagnostic manuals and tools used, and the different autism profiles presented by individuals. Read more:\nhttps://www.autism.org.uk/advice-and-guidance/what-is-autism/asperger-syndrome\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are the complications associated with Autism?",
        "Answer": "Problems with social interactions, communication and behavior can lead to:\n1. Problems in school and with successful learning\n2. Employment problems\n3. Inability to live independently\n4. Social isolation\n5. Stress within the family\n5. Victimization and being bullied\nRead more:\nhttps://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/autism-spectrum-disorder/symptoms-causes/syc-20352928\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are the complications of ASD?",
        "Answer": "Problems with social interactions, communication and behavior can lead to:\n1. Problems in school and with successful learning\n2. Employment problems\n3. Inability to live independently\n4. Social isolation\n5. Stress within the family\n5. Victimization and being bullied\nRead more:\nhttps://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/autism-spectrum-disorder/symptoms-causes/syc-20352928\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are Screening Tools for Autism?",
        "Answer": "There are many different developmental screening tools that may be administered by professionals, community service providers, and in some cases, parents. These include:\n1. Ages and Stages Questionnaires (ASQ)\n2. Communication and Symbolic Behavior Scales (CSBS)\n3. Parent's Evaluation of Development Status (PEDS)\n4. Modified Checklist for Autism in Toddlers (M-CHAT)\n5. Screening Tool for Autism in Toddlers and Young Children (STAT)\n6. Observation tools such as the Autism Diagnostic Observation Schedule (ADOS-G)\n7. The Childhood Autism Rating Scale (CARS)\n8. The Autism Diagnostic Interview Revised (ADI-R)\nThese lists are not exhaustive, and other tests are available.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/is-it-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are the co-occurring conditions that can occur with autism?",
        "Answer": "Several medical conditions are associated with autism, and they are often referred to as comorbidities or co-occurring conditions. These can include seizures, sensory sensitivities, anxiety, and sleep disturbances as well as gastrointestinal, metabolic, and immune dysregulation. Talk with your doctor to identify and treat such conditions.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/symptoms-of-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are the comorbidities that comes with autism?",
        "Answer": "Several medical conditions are associated with autism, and they are often referred to as comorbidities or co-occurring conditions. These can include seizures, sensory sensitivities, anxiety, and sleep disturbances as well as gastrointestinal, metabolic, and immune dysregulation. Talk with your doctor to identify and treat such conditions.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/symptoms-of-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "I am a female with suspected ASD, but professionals and others have tended to discount my suspicions. What should I do?",
        "Answer": "While diagnoses of ASD in males continue to increase, the referrals and diagnoses for women have not followed this pattern and females may be diagnosed later in life, especially if they are considered 'high functioning'. There are a few possible reasons for this, including socialization to a 'gender role'\u009d, better abilities to cope with stressful situations, and better developed social skills. Signs and symptoms of an ASD may be less obvious. Therefore, it is important to see a diagnostician who is familiar with the presentation of ASD in females.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autismontario.com/sites/default/files/2020-04/Getting%20a%20Diagnosis%20of%20ASD_0.pdf\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Are there other diseases that have the same symptoms of autism?",
        "Answer": "At least seven disorders are part of or closely related to Autism. Each disorder has symptoms commonly seen with autism, as well as its own specific symptoms.\n1. Williams Syndrome\n2. Fragile X Syndrome\n3. Landau-Kleffner Syndrome\n4. Prader-Willi Syndrome\n5. Angelman Syndrome\n6. Rett Syndrome\n7. Tardive Dyskinesia\nRead More:\nhttps://www.autism.org/related-disorders/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is the prognosis of children with Autism?",
        "Answer": "The prognosis in patients with autism is highly correlated with their IQ. Low-functioning patients may never live independently; they typically need home or residential care for the rest of their lives. High-functioning patients may live independently, hold jobs successfully, and even marry and have children.\nRead More:\nhttps://www.news-medical.net/health/Autism-Prognosis.aspx\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Are dietary interventions helpful to autistic children?",
        "Answer": "Dietary interventions such as restrictive diets or supplements are common treatments for young people with autism spectrum disorder (ASD). Evidence for the efficacy of these interventions is still controversial. A study published by the American Academy of Pediatrics does not support nonspecific dietary interventions as treatment of ASD but suggests a potential role for some specific dietary interventions in the management of some symptoms, functions, and clinical domains in patients with ASD.\n\nRead more:\nhttps://pediatrics.aappublications.org/content/144/5/e20183218\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Are medications useful in treating the behavioral problems of Autistic children?",
        "Answer": "Research shows that medication is most effective when used in combination with behavioral therapies. The FDA has approved the use of some antipsychotic drugs, such as risperidone and aripripazole, for treating irritability associated with ASD in children between certain ages. Parents should talk with their child's healthcare providers about any medications for children with ASD.\n\nRead more:\nhttps://www.nichd.nih.gov/health/topics/autism/conditioninfo/treatments/medication-treatment\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Do autistic children commonly suffer from other illnesses?",
        "Answer": "The conditions that overlap with autism generally fall into one of four groups: classic medical problems, such as epilepsy, gastrointestinal issues or sleep disorders; developmental diagnoses, such as intellectual disability or language delay; mental-health conditions, such as attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD), obsessive-compulsive disorder or depression; and genetic conditions, including fragile X syndrome and tuberous sclerosis complex.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.spectrumnews.org/news/conditions-accompany-autism-explained/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How are Anxiety and depression treated in an autistic person?",
        "Answer": "Cognitive-behavioral therapy (CBT) is the most widely used behavioral therapy shown to be effective at reducing symptoms of depression in ASD. Many CBT programs have been adapted for the ASD population and focus on anxiety and aggression in addition to depression. Other behavioral therapies shown as being effective at treating depression in ASD include mindfulness-based therapy, social and vocational skills programs, and family therapy.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.psychiatryadvisor.com/home/depression-advisor/depression-with-autism-effective-diagnosis-and-treatment/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How can I get my autistic child to exercise?",
        "Answer": "Identify the activities your child enjoys, such as jumping on a trampoline, swimming or riding a bicycle. Work toward increasing the time available for these activities. Determine the length of time your child participates in these activities and set small goals to increase that time. Start with just a few more minutes spent on each activity or by adding one other opportunity during the week when your child can participate. While tablets, computers and television might be useful in small amounts for learning opportunities or as rewards, too much screen time can take away from time spent in active play.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.marcus.org/autism-resources/autism-tips-and-resources/helping-kids-with-autism-stay-active\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Is Naltrexone helpful in treating autism?",
        "Answer": "Low-dose Naltrexone (LDN) has shown to be an effective pharmacologic intervention for autism. Parents of children with autism were surveyed and 75 percent of them reported that LDN is 'overall beneficial'\u009d for their children as they noted significant improvement in cognition, communication, and socialization. Research also showed additional positive effects: a decline in hyperactivity, restlessness, inattention, and aggression in young children with autism.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.compoundingcenter.com/blog/ldn-autism\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Is Secretin helpful in treating the symptoms of Autism?",
        "Answer": "Several anecdotal reports suggested that secretin, a gastrointestinal hormone that may function as a neurotransmitter, was an effective intervention for the symptoms of autism. This led to several scientific studies of secretin for children with autism spectrum disorders.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.medscape.com/answers/912781-193718/what-is-the-role-of-secretin-therapy-in-the-treatment-of-autism-spectrum-disorder-asd\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Is there an association between autism and Tourette's syndrome?",
        "Answer": "Lancaster University researchers have discovered, for the first time, a common genetic link between autism and Tourette's impairs brain communication.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.eurekalert.org/news-releases/872549\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Is there truth to the claim that the number of children with autism has been increasing ever since the Thimerosal has been in use?",
        "Answer": "A worldwide increase in the rate of autism diagnoses likely driven by broadened diagnostic criteria and increased awareness has fueled concerns that an environmental exposure like vaccines might cause autism. Theories for this putative association have centered on the measles-mumps-rubella (MMR) vaccine, thimerosal, and the large number of vaccines currently administered. However, both epidemiological and biological studies fail to support these claims.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2908388/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Is ia true that the number of children with autism has been increasing ever since the MMR vaccinehas been in use?",
        "Answer": "A worldwide increase in the rate of autism diagnoses likely driven by broadened diagnostic criteria and increased awareness has fueled concerns that an environmental exposure like vaccines might cause autism. Theories for this putative association have centered on the measles-mumps-rubella (MMR) vaccine, thimerosal, and the large number of vaccines currently administered. However, both epidemiological and biological studies fail to support these claims.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2908388/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Does Thimerosal cause autism?",
        "Answer": "A worldwide increase in the rate of autism diagnoses likely driven by broadened diagnostic criteria and increased awareness has fueled concerns that an environmental exposure like vaccines might cause autism. Theories for this putative association have centered on the measles-mumps-rubella (MMR) vaccine, thimerosal, and the large number of vaccines currently administered. However, both epidemiological and biological studies fail to support these claims.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2908388/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Can anti-seizure medication be helpful in treating some behavior problems associated with autism?",
        "Answer": "Anti-seizure medications (anticonvulsants) are another group of medications that had demonstrated effectiveness in treating behavioral symptoms in austitic patients. Researchers have noticed that while treating austistic children for their seizures, their aggressive behavoirs improved while on anticonvulsants.\nRead more:\nhttps://books.google.com.sg/books?id=LtqUAChbC98C&dq=I%E2%80%99ve+heard+that+anti-seizure+medication+can+be+helpful+in+treating+some+behavior+problems+associated+with+autism.+Is+that+true%3F&source=gbs_navlinks_s\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What medications are used to treat seizures in autistic children?",
        "Answer": "Anti-seizure medications (anticonvulsants) are another group of medications that had demonstrated effectiveness in treating behavioral symptoms in austitic patients. Researchers have noticed that while treating austistic children for their seizures, their aggressive behavoirs improved while on anticonvulsants.\nRead more:\nhttps://books.google.com.sg/books?id=LtqUAChbC98C&dq=I%E2%80%99ve+heard+that+anti-seizure+medication+can+be+helpful+in+treating+some+behavior+problems+associated+with+autism.+Is+that+true%3F&source=gbs_navlinks_s\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "My child was just diagnosed with Autism. What do I do first?",
        "Answer": "Give yourself time. Know that help and support is available, there are many organizations and support groups available on the internent and in your local community. Even if things are hard now, they can get better. You or your child are still the same person as before.\nUnderstand that autism is not an illness or disease with treatments or a \"cure\" and autistic people have things they're good at as well as things they need help with.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.nhs.uk/conditions/autism/newly-diagnosed/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Traveling with my autistic child is difficult. What can I do to make 'going out'\u00c2\u009d easier?",
        "Answer": "Preparing is the most important part of the trip! Make sure your child knows as much as possible about what will happen on the vacation. One easy way to front-load is to view You tube videos of where you are going.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autismspeaks.org/blog/my-tips-going-vacation-kids-autism\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are some treatments for involuntary movements, vocalizations and Tourette's Syndrome associated with Autism?",
        "Answer": "Mild tics that don't affect everyday activities might not need treatment. However, severe tics can make it hard to function at work, school or in social situations. Some tics even lead to self-injury. In these cases, medication or behavioral therapy may help.\nRead more:\nhttps://my.clevelandclinic.org/health/diseases/5554-tourette-syndrome#management-and-treatment\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is Childhood Disintegrative Disorder?",
        "Answer": "Childhood disintegrative disorder is a condition in which children develop normally through age 3 or 4. Then, over a few months, they lose language, motor, social, and other skills that they already learned.  Childhood disintegrative disorder is a part of the larger developmental disorder category of autism spectrum disorder.\nRead more:\nhttps://medlineplus.gov/ency/article/001535.htm\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is Pervasive Developmental Disorder '\u00e2\u20ac\u0153 Not otherwise Specified (PDD-NOS)? ",
        "Answer": "Pervasive Developmental Disorder '\u20ac\u0153 Not Otherwise Specified (PDD-NOS) refers to a group of disorders characterised by impairment in the development of social interaction, verbal and non-verbal communication, imaginative activity and a limited number of interests and activities that tend to be repetitive.\nRead more:\nhttps://childdevelopment.com.au/areas-of-concern/diagnoses/pervasive-developmental-disorder-not-otherwise-specified-pdd-nos/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is Respite Care?",
        "Answer": "Respite care provides temporary relief for a primary caregiver, enabling you to take a much-needed break from the demands of caregiving a sick, aging, or disabled family member. Respite care can take place in your own home, at day-care centers, or at residential or nursing facilities that offer overnight stays.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.helpguide.org/articles/caregiving/respite-care.htm\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What type of computer should an autistic child use?",
        "Answer": "One of the models of Asus Eee PCs, many of which are less expensive that the Amazon Kindle, and yet are fully-functional sub-laptops. With a little customization of parental controls and adding the right software, a computer like this could be perfect for a kid with, or without the challenge of austism.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.google.com/amp/s/www.wired.com/2009/01/whats-the-best-2/amp\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What kind of home is good for people with autism?",
        "Answer": "Many people with autism live at home or with a friend or family member. When additional support is needed, in-home services may include a companion, homemaking/housekeeping, therapy and health services or personal care. Respite Care. Some individuals with autism remain in their parents' home far into their adult years.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.easterseals.com/explore-resources/living-with-autism/autism-after-age-21.html\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Where do Autistic People Usually Live?",
        "Answer": "Many people with autism live at home or with a friend or family member. When additional support is needed, in-home services may include a companion, homemaking/housekeeping, therapy and health services or personal care. Respite Care. Some individuals with autism remain in their parents' home far into their adult years.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.easterseals.com/explore-resources/living-with-autism/autism-after-age-21.html\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Are there other therapies that are useful in treatment of behavioral symptoms in Autistic children?",
        "Answer": "Educational/behavioral therapies are often effective in children with autism, with Applied Behavioral Analysis (ABA) usually being the most effective. ABA may be an effective adjunctive treatment in reinforcing desirable and reducing undesirable behaviors. ABA has significantly more published scientific support than any other form of educational therapy. These methods can be used together with dietary and medical interventions, as together they offer the best chance for improvement.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/advice-for-parents/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Are there other useful  treatment of behavioral problems in Autistic children?",
        "Answer": "Educational/behavioral therapies are often effective in children with autism, with Applied Behavioral Analysis (ABA) usually being the most effective. ABA may be an effective adjunctive treatment in reinforcing desirable and reducing undesirable behaviors. ABA has significantly more published scientific support than any other form of educational therapy. These methods can be used together with dietary and medical interventions, as together they offer the best chance for improvement.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/advice-for-parents/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Is Asperger syndrome also on the spectrum of autism disorders?",
        "Answer": "A condition also on the spectrum of autism disorders is Asperger syndrome (AS), which is characterized by social impairment, communication difficulties, and restrictive, repetitive, and stereotyped patterns of behavior. Autism spectrum disorders (ASDs) are a type of neurodevelopmental disorder that is present from infancy or early childhood. Other types of ASDs include autistic disorder, childhood disintegrative disorder, and pervasive developmental disorder not otherwise specified (usually referred to as PDD-NOS).\nRead more:\nhttps://www.emedicinehealth.com/autism_spectrum_disorder_quiz_iq/faq.htm\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Does autism include a broad spectrum of symptoms and disorders?",
        "Answer": "The term \"autism\" is generally used to describe a group of complex developmental brain disorders known as Pervasive Developmental Disorders (PDD). These disorders include Asperger Syndrome, Rett Syndrome, and Childhood Disintegrative Disorder. Many parents and professionals refer to this group as Autism Spectrum Disorders.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.emedicinehealth.com/autism_spectrum_disorder_quiz_iq/faq.htm\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Is Autism a neuropsychiatric disorder?",
        "Answer": "Autism spectrum disorder (ASD), often referred to as simply autism, is a developmental disability that impacts how people communicate verbally and nonverbally, and how they interact, behave, and learn. People with ASD don't look different, but the way they interact with the world around them is different. The way people with ASD learn, think, and problem solve can vary from being gifted in math, art, music, or visual skills, to being severely challenged both mentally and physically. Many people with ASD can live independently, while some need assistance in daily living.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.emedicinehealth.com/autism_spectrum_disorder_quiz_iq/faq.htm\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Do autistic people look different?",
        "Answer": "Autism is a neurodevelopmental (meaning related to the brain) disability and doesn't have any physical characteristics. This can lead to others judging autistic individuals and their families, because they may not understand why the autistic individual is behaving differently. Social interactions are subtle and constantly changing, and autistic people may have challenges keeping up with verbal and non-verbal messages that are being communicated. Their behaviour may be misunderstood and believed to be rude.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.amaze.org.au/understand-autism/about-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How are autistic people different?",
        "Answer": "Autism is a neurodevelopmental (meaning related to the brain) disability and doesn't have any physical characteristics. This can lead to others judging autistic individuals and their families, because they may not understand why the autistic individual is behaving differently. Social interactions are subtle and constantly changing, and autistic people may have challenges keeping up with verbal and non-verbal messages that are being communicated. Their behaviour may be misunderstood and believed to be rude.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.amaze.org.au/understand-autism/about-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Does autism often occur with other disorders?",
        "Answer": "Yes, autism often occurs alongside other conditions, including intellectual disability, seizure disorder (epilepsy), language delay, attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) and behaviour disorders such as oppositional defiant disorder, as well as anxiety and genetic disorders such as Fragile X and Down Syndrome. Sometimes these other conditions will have a greater impact on a child's ability to function at school and home than the autism itself. \u00a0Intellectual disability and autism spectrum disorder frequently occur together.\nRead more:\nhttps://rockmelon.com/about-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How are Austism Diagnosed?",
        "Answer": "To date, no biological diagnostic tests exist that detect autism. But scientists are hopeful that advanced imaging techniques and differences in blood levels of proteins in autistic versus normal children may have implications for diagnosis. Formal diagnosis involves parental input and structured and systematic screening instruments, such as the Modified Checklist for Autism in Toddlers (M-CHAT) and the Autism Behavioral Checklist (ABC) for older children. The Childhood Autism Rating Scale (CARS) and the Autism Diagnostic Inventory-Revised (ADI-R) are used, as well. A formal diagnosis of autism requires an evaluation by an experienced psychiatrist, psychologist, neurologist, or developmental pediatrician (a pediatrician who specializes in developmental disorders).\nRead more:\nhttps://www.bbrfoundation.org/faq/frequently-asked-questions-about-autism\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How is autism diagnosed in young children?",
        "Answer": "To date, no biological diagnostic tests exist that detect autism. But scientists are hopeful that advanced imaging techniques and differences in blood levels of proteins in autistic versus normal children may have implications for diagnosis. Formal diagnosis involves parental input and structured and systematic screening instruments, such as the Modified Checklist for Autism in Toddlers (M-CHAT) and the Autism Behavioral Checklist (ABC) for older children. The Childhood Autism Rating Scale (CARS) and the Autism Diagnostic Inventory-Revised (ADI-R) are used, as well. A formal diagnosis of autism requires an evaluation by an experienced psychiatrist, psychologist, neurologist, or developmental pediatrician (a pediatrician who specializes in developmental disorders).\nRead more:\nhttps://www.bbrfoundation.org/faq/frequently-asked-questions-about-autism\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How is Asperger syndrome diagnosed?",
        "Answer": "The characteristics of Asperger syndrome vary from one person to another, although there are some key traits that autistic people share.\u00a0These are: \u00a0\n- persistent difficulties with or differences in social communication and social interaction\u00a0\n- restricted and repetitive patterns of behaviours, activities or interests since early childhood, to the extent that these impact negatively on day to day life.\nThe diagnosis process usually involves a multi-disciplinary diagnostic team - often including a speech and language therapist, paediatrician, psychiatrist and/or psychologist.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org.uk/advice-and-guidance/what-is-autism/asperger-syndrome\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How is Autism Treated?",
        "Answer": "Treatment for autism depends largely on the individual and what challenges they face; however, it is widely accepted that the earliest interventions allow the best outcomes.\u00a0Behavioral therapies are the mainstay of treatment for most autistic people. Those who need it may also receive speech-language therapy, social skills training, and occupational therapy. Parents may also receive training on how better to work with their autistic child at home. Intense early intervention has been shown to be highly effective, and there are an array of programs geared to different types of needs. \nRead more:\nhttps://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/autism-spectrum-disorder/diagnosis-treatment/drc-20352934\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Does  early intervention yield better results for autism?",
        "Answer": "Treatment for autism depends largely on the individual and what challenges they face; however, it is widely accepted that the earliest interventions allow the best outcomes.\u00a0Behavioral therapies are the mainstay of treatment for most autistic people. Those who need it may also receive speech-language therapy, social skills training, and occupational therapy. Parents may also receive training on how better to work with their autistic child at home. Intense early intervention has been shown to be highly effective, and there are an array of programs geared to different types of needs. \nRead more:\nhttps://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/autism-spectrum-disorder/diagnosis-treatment/drc-20352934\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How can I be sure vaccines have nothing to do with autism?",
        "Answer": "Immunizations are a cornerstone of public health and protect people from many debilitating and deadly infectious diseases. Government agencies routinely conduct thorough analyses of the current medical and scientific evidence on vaccine safety and vaccine-related adverse events. While there is evidence of some rare adverse events related to vaccines, such as seizures, inflammation of the brain and fainting, the evidence shows that there are no links between immunization and autism.\nRead more:\nhttps://iancommunity.org/autism-faq\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How can you tell the difference with Autism from Asperger's Syndrome?",
        "Answer": "The diagnosis of Asperger syndrome was characterized as a subtype of high-functioning autism. Most individuals diagnosed with Asperger syndrome were described as 'social but awkward.'\u009d That is, they want to have friends, but found it particularly challenging to begin and/or maintain a friendship. Like their peers on the spectrum, high-functioning autistic individuals were often delayed in developing speech/language. Those with Asperger syndrome tended not to have speech/language delays, but their speech was usually described as peculiar, such as being stilted and perseverating on unusual topics. \nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/advice-for-parents/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How common is Asperger syndrome?",
        "Answer": "Asperger syndrome, is much more common than most people think. There are around 700,000 autistic people in the UK '\u20ac\u0153 that's more than 1 in 100. People with Asperger syndrome come from all nationalities and cultural, religious and social backgrounds. \u00a0Historically, more men have been diagnosed as autistic than\u00a0women, although this is beginning to change.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org.uk/advice-and-guidance/what-is-autism/asperger-syndrome\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How do people with Asperger syndrome see the world?",
        "Answer": "Some people with Asperger syndrome say the world feels overwhelming and this can cause them considerable anxiety. In particular, understanding and relating to other people, and taking part in everyday family, school, work and social life, can be harder. People with Asperger syndrome may wonder why they are 'different' and feel their social differences mean people don't understand them.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org.uk/advice-and-guidance/what-is-autism/asperger-syndrome\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Is it useful for an older adult (40+) to be diagnosed with ASD?",
        "Answer": "Sometimes it can be useful for an older adult to receive a diagnosis. If they are functioning well without a formal diagnosis, or if a diagnostic assessment would not mean any change in their selfperception, services available to them, or treatment approach used, a full assessment may not be necessary.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autismontario.com/sites/default/files/2020-04/Getting%20a%20Diagnosis%20of%20ASD_0.pdf\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Are childhood vaccines (like MMR) responsible for autism spectrum disorders?",
        "Answer": "Available epidemiological data show that there is no evidence of a link between measles-mumps-rubella (MMR) vaccine and autism spectrum disorders. Previous studies suggesting a causal link were found to be seriously flawed. There is also no evidence to suggest that any other childhood vaccine may increase the risk of autism spectrum disorders.  In addition, evidence reviews commissioned by WHO concluded that there was no association between the use of vaccine preservatives such as thiomersal and autism spectrum disorders.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.who.int/news-room/q-a-detail/autism-spectrum-disorders-(asd)\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Will childhood vaccines cause autism spectrum disorders?",
        "Answer": "Available epidemiological data show that there is no evidence of a link between measles-mumps-rubella (MMR) vaccine and autism spectrum disorders. Previous studies suggesting a causal link were found to be seriously flawed. There is also no evidence to suggest that any other childhood vaccine may increase the risk of autism spectrum disorders.  In addition, evidence reviews commissioned by WHO concluded that there was no association between the use of vaccine preservatives such as thiomersal and autism spectrum disorders.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.who.int/news-room/q-a-detail/autism-spectrum-disorders-(asd)\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Is there a link between MMR Vaccine and the development of Autism?",
        "Answer": "Available epidemiological data show that there is no evidence of a link between measles-mumps-rubella (MMR) vaccine and autism spectrum disorders. Previous studies suggesting a causal link were found to be seriously flawed. There is also no evidence to suggest that any other childhood vaccine may increase the risk of autism spectrum disorders.  In addition, evidence reviews commissioned by WHO concluded that there was no association between the use of vaccine preservatives such as thiomersal and autism spectrum disorders.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.who.int/news-room/q-a-detail/autism-spectrum-disorders-(asd)\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Are all children routinely tested for mitochondrial diseases? What about children with autism?",
        "Answer": "Children are not routinely tested for mitochondrial diseases. This includes children with autism and other developmental delays.\nTesting is not easy and may involve getting multiple samples of blood, and often samples of muscle. Doctors decide whether testing for mitochondrial diseases should be done based on a child's signs and symptoms.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.cdc.gov/ncbddd/autism/topics.html\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Can adults be diagnosed with autism?",
        "Answer": "Yes, adults can be diagnosed with an ASD. Diagnosis includes looking at the person's medical history, watching the person's behavior, and giving the person some psychological tests. But, it can be more challenging to diagnose an adult because it is not always possible to know about the person's development during the first few years of life, and a long history of other diagnoses may complicate an ASD diagnosis.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.cdc.gov/ncbddd/autism/topics.html\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are mitochondrial diseases or disorders?",
        "Answer": "Mitochondria are tiny parts of almost every cell in your body. Mitochondria are like the power house of the cells. They turn sugar and oxygen into energy that the cells need to work. In mitochondrial diseases, the mitochondria cannot efficiently turn sugar and oxygen into energy, so the cells do not work correctly. Not everyone with a mitochondrial disease will show symptoms. However, when discussing the group of mitochondrial diseases that tend to affect children, symptoms usually appear in the toddler and preschool years.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.cdc.gov/ncbddd/autism/topics.html\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are the other forms of ASDs (besides Autism and Asperger's Syndrome)?",
        "Answer": "Other disorders in the spectrum include pervasive developmental disorder not otherwise specified (PDDNOS) and two rarer disorders: childhood disintegrative disorder (CDD) and Rett's syndrome. Children with PDDNOS demonstrate symptoms similar to autistic disorder, but do not meet all criteria for the disorder. Children with CDD, which affects more boys than girls, develop normally until approximately the first two years of life (average onset of symptoms is between 3 and 4 years) but they then regress in most areas and continue worsening. Specifically, they experience a pronounced loss in motor, language, social and intellectual skills. Seizures may even occur.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.bbrfoundation.org/faq/frequently-asked-questions-about-autism\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What disorders are related to austism?",
        "Answer": "Certain known genetic disorders are associated with an increased risk for autism, including Fragile X syndrome and tuberous sclerosis, each of which results from a mutation in a single, but different gene. Recently, researchers have discovered other genetic mutations in children diagnosed with autism, including some that have not yet been designated as named syndromes. People with ASD also have a higher than average risk of having epilepsy. Children whose language skills regress early in life before age 3 appear to have a risk of developing epilepsy or seizure-like brain activity.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.ninds.nih.gov/Disorders/Patient-Caregiver-Education/Fact-Sheets/Autism-Spectrum-Disorder-Fact-Sheet#3082_5\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is Asperger's Syndrome?",
        "Answer": "Asperger's Syndrome is the second most common ASD and is a milder form of autism. Children with Asperger's Syndrome exhibit higher language development than children with autism and often have normal intellectual ability combined with a disinterest in social communication. Children with Asperger's may not initiate or sustain a conversation and do not compensate for their limited language by using nonverbal means of communication, thus limiting their peer relationships. Similar to autism, children with Asperger's do not share enjoyment or interests with others.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.bbrfoundation.org/faq/frequently-asked-questions-about-autism\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is Autistic Disorder?",
        "Answer": "Autistic disorder, commonly referred to as autism, is the most prevalent ASD and severely impairs a child's social interaction and communication abilities.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.bbrfoundation.org/faq/frequently-asked-questions-about-autism\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is Rett Syndrome?",
        "Answer": "Rett syndrome is a genetic disorder almost exclusively found in females. After early normal development, autistic symptoms begin to develop between 6 and 18 months, which typically include shunning social contact, talking cessation, unique motor behaviors, and a regression in skills. A single gene mutation has been identified as a cause of Rett syndrome, a finding that may enable researchers to develop improved diagnostics, earlier interventions and better treatments for the condition.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.bbrfoundation.org/faq/frequently-asked-questions-about-autism\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What types of medications are used to treat autistic children?",
        "Answer": "Because autism spectrum disorder can't be cured, many parents seek alternative or complementary therapies, but these treatments have little or no research to show that they're effective. You could, unintentionally, reinforce negative behaviors. And some alternative treatments are potentially dangerous. Talk with your child's doctor about the scientific evidence of any therapy that you're considering for your child. with animals improves symptoms of autism spectrum disorder.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/autism-spectrum-disorder/diagnosis-treatment/drc-20352934\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What treatments are recommended or not recommended for ASD?",
        "Answer": "Because autism spectrum disorder can't be cured, many parents seek alternative or complementary therapies, but these treatments have little or no research to show that they're effective. You could, unintentionally, reinforce negative behaviors. And some alternative treatments are potentially dangerous. Talk with your child's doctor about the scientific evidence of any therapy that you're considering for your child. with animals improves symptoms of autism spectrum disorder.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/autism-spectrum-disorder/diagnosis-treatment/drc-20352934\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Why do concerns about mercury in vaccines persist?",
        "Answer": "Concerns about the thimerosal -autism link persist for a number of reasons. Methylmercury is unquestionably a toxic substance and there is warranted concern about exposure to many toxins present in the environment.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.necc.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/AutismFAQ.pdf\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Why do people diagnosed with autism spectrum disorder (ASD) sometimes have a difficult time making eye contact?",
        "Answer": "Researchers recently have found that people diagnosed with ASD have a hard time making eye contact. In one study, the subcortical system of the brain was shown to exhibit a high activation, which researchers believe may be the basis of people with autism avoiding eye contact in daily life. This pathway is involved in facial recognition and detection. In infants, the more this pathway is used, the better the visual cortex develops. This can help give the person diagnosed with autism and their loved ones an improved ability to recognize social cues and communicate with one another.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.healthline.com/health/our-two-cents-doctors-answer-questions-about-autism\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How do I choose the best special education program for my autistic child?",
        "Answer": "It's important then to understand what your child's strengths and needs are,  physically, emotionally and mentally, and to look for a school which can effectively match these. You should also keep in mind that you want to find a school that will continue to be suitable over the years as your child's strengths and needs change. When considering potential schools, you also need to think about things such as your family's values, beliefs, budget, available time, and more.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.skillsyouneed.com/rhubarb/choose-school-for-special-needs.html\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How do I obtain Guardianship for my autistic child?",
        "Answer": "Here are the steps to getting legal guardianship:\n1. Fill out forms at probate court and ask for a hearing.\n2. The court will determine when you'll need to be present for a hearing to determine guardianship.\n3. The adult child will be evaluated by a doctor or other mental health professional to determine how well you make decisions.\n4. At the hearing, the doctor or mental health professional will present his or her findings about the adult child's level of competence.\n5. The judge will determine what level of guardianship an individual may need.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.thesimpledollar.com/financial-wellness/guide-to-guardianship-for-young-adults-with-disabilities/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is the educational model called Floor Time?",
        "Answer": "Floortime is a relationship-based therapy for children with autism. The intervention is called Floortime because the parent gets down on the floor with the child to play and interact with the child at their level.The goal is for adults to help children expand their circles of communication. They meet the child at their developmental level and build on their strengths. Therapists and parents engage children through the activities each child enjoys. They enter the child's games. They follow the child's lead.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autismspeaks.org/floortime-0\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Keeping my child clean and neat is a real challenge. How do other parents deal with this?",
        "Answer": "Here are some suggetions to keep your child clean:\n1)  Explore alternatives for showering like sponge bath or washing with a damp clo\nthes when the child is watching TV or playing video games\n2)For some children cutting finger or toe nails is frightening. So do this while they are distracted or asleep.\n3) If your child is afraid of getting his/her haircut then try brushing hair regularly to \ndesensitize your child to getting a hair cut\nRead more:\nhttps://books.google.co.in/books?id=LtqUAChbC98C&pg=PA194&lpg=PA194&dq=Keeping+my+child+clean+and+neat+is+a+real+challenge.+autism&source=bl&ots=vEBPNuDStr&sig=ACfU3U3kNCPfEUL5CvxOMoleJd4oea9Nmw&hl=en&sa=X&ved=2ahUKEwiopsrbrNPyAhUVeisKHb5mC6AQ6AF6BAg7EAM#v=onepage&q=Keeping%20my%20child%20clean%20and%20neat%20is%20a%20real%20challenge.%20autism&f=false\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How do I keep my child clean and neat?",
        "Answer": "Here are some suggetions to keep your child clean:\n1)  Explore alternatives for showering like sponge bath or washing with a damp clo\nthes when the child is watching TV or playing video games\n2)For some children cutting finger or toe nails is frightening. So do this while they are distracted or asleep.\n3) If your child is afraid of getting his/her haircut then try brushing hair regularly to \ndesensitize your child to getting a hair cut\n\nRead more:\nhttps://books.google.co.in/books?id=LtqUAChbC98C&pg=PA194&lpg=PA194&dq=Keeping+my+child+clean+and+neat+is+a+real+challenge.+autism&source=bl&ots=vEBPNuDStr&sig=ACfU3U3kNCPfEUL5CvxOMoleJd4oea9Nmw&hl=en&sa=X&ved=2ahUKEwiopsrbrNPyAhUVeisKHb5mC6AQ6AF6BAg7EAM#v=onepage&q=Keeping%20my%20child%20clean%20and%20neat%20is%20a%20real%20challenge.%20autism&f=false\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are some resources for learning more about autism?",
        "Answer": "Searching for autism information on the web can be overwhelming\nSo We created this list of web resources based on recommendations from leading ASD organizations.\n1)Asperger Syndrome and High Functioning Autism Association\n2)Autism Highway\n3)Autism Research Institute\n4)Autism Society\nRead more:\nhttps://www.readingrockets.org/article/top-autism-organizations-and-web-resources\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What does the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 have to do with the education of my child?",
        "Answer": "Section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 requires recipients to provide to students with disabilities appropriate educational services designed to meet the individual needs of such students to the same extent as the needs of students without disabilities are met. An appropriate education for a student with a disability under the Section 504 regulations could consist of education in regular classrooms, education in regular classes with supplementary services, and/or special education and related services.\nRead more:\nhttps://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ocr/504faq.html\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is a \"Letter of Intent\" and why is it necessary when creating a special needs trust?",
        "Answer": "An important companion piece to a special needs trust is a 'letter of intent' or 'letter of instruction'. This is a document that actually ensures your trustee knows your child's functional abilities, routines, interests, and particular likes and dislikes. In addition to describing your special child, the letter of intent identifies specific doctors, services and resources that will help your child enjoy the highest level of independence and self-reliance. The document is a valuable tool that communicates knowledge only parents may know, including specific hopes and desires for their child's future well being, to the very people who will be caring for the child after the parents no longer are able to do so.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.specialneedsalliance.org/the-voice/letter-of-intent-4/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is a special needs trust?",
        "Answer": "A special needs trust is a legal arrangement and fiduciary relationship that allows a physically or mentally disabled or chronically ill person to receive income without reducing their eligibility for the public assistance disability benefits provided by Social Security, Supplemental Security Income, Medicare or Medicaid. In a fiduciary relationship, a person or entity acts on behalf of another person or people to manage assets.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.investopedia.com/terms/s/special-needs-trust.asp\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is guardianship?",
        "Answer": "A guardian is a person who has assumed the care and protection of another person, and is responsible for all legal decisions on behalf of that person, and his property. All parents are legal guardians of their child(ren) till the child attains 18 years of age. Persons with Autism are in a special situation because even after they reach 18 years of age, they are not seen as being adequate to manage or take any legal decisions for their betterment. The National Trust Act, therefore, enables a person with above disabilities to have a guardian representing her/him throughout their lives.\nRead more:\nhttps://vikaspedia.in/education/parents-corner/guidelines-for-parents-of-children-with-disabilities/guardianship#:~:text=Autism%2C%20cerebral%20palsy%2C%20mental%20retardation%20and%20multiple%20disabilities,-Persons%20with%20Autism&text=As%20per%20the%20Act%2C%20a,till%20their%20child%20turns%20%2D18.\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is special education?",
        "Answer": "Special education, is the practice of educating students in a way that provides accommodations that address their individual differences, disabilities, and special needs. Ideally, this process involves the individually planned and systematically monitored arrangement of teaching procedures, adapted equipment and materials, and accessible settings. These interventions are designed to help individuals with special needs achieve a higher level of personal self-sufficiency and success \nRead more:\nhttps://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Special_education\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is the Individualized Education Plan (IEP)?",
        "Answer": "This is a plan or program developed to ensure that a child with an identified disability who is attending an elementary or secondary educational institution receives specialized instruction and related services. The IEP is developed by a team of individuals from various educational disciplines, the child with a disability, family members, and/or designated advocates.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.washington.edu/accesscomputing/what-individualized-education-plan\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What should a parent do about childhood immunizations?",
        "Answer": "Many vaccines are given more than once, at different ages, and in combinations. This means that you'll need to keep a careful record of your child's shots. Common side effects of immunizations include swelling at the site of the injection, soreness, and fever. Discuss these side effects with your doctor and ask what symptoms deserve an office call. Always bring your immunizations record with you to all of your child's office visits and make sure the doctor signs and dates every immunization.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.stanfordchildrens.org/en/topic/default?id=why-childhood-immunizations-are-important-1-4510\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Why do I need to establish guardianship for my adult child?",
        "Answer": "All parents are legal guardians of their child(ren) only till the child attains 18 years of age. Although, parents may take the full responsibility of looking after their child, even after the child is 18 years old, they will need to legally represent their child as a guardian in  many situations such as:\n1) To safeguard the interest of disabled when involved in a crime.\n2) for obtaining loans and concessions.\nRead more:\nhttps://vikaspedia.in/education/parents-corner/guidelines-for-parents-of-children-with-disabilities/guardianship\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Can diet help children with autism spectrum disorder?",
        "Answer": "Families have reported improvements in behavior and language as a result of special diets, including elimination diets that remove gluten (a protein in wheat and related grains) and casein (a protein in milk). However, research results do not support the widespread use of elimination diets as a treatment for autism symptoms.\nRead more:\nhttps://icahn.mssm.edu/research/seaver/resources/autism-faqs\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How do I find help for my autistic child?",
        "Answer": "Start by making sure that you and your child have an effective and reputable healthcare team on your side, which may include physicians, counselors, occupational therapists, and Special Education teachers. Be sure that any health care professional you talk to focuses on your child's holistic well-being: physical, mental, emotional and behavioral health as well as educational goals and life skills. Finally, get connected to an established network of parents who are facing the same questions and challenges.\nRead more:\nhttps://springbrookbehavioral.com/frequently-asked-questions-about-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Where can I find assistance for my autistic child?",
        "Answer": "Start by making sure that you and your child have an effective and reputable healthcare team on your side, which may include physicians, counselors, occupational therapists, and Special Education teachers. Be sure that any health care professional you talk to focuses on your child's holistic well-being: physical, mental, emotional and behavioral health as well as educational goals and life skills. Finally, get connected to an established network of parents who are facing the same questions and challenges.\nRead more:\nhttps://springbrookbehavioral.com/frequently-asked-questions-about-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How can I find out if me or my autistic child's case is genetic?",
        "Answer": "If your child has autism and you are interested in genetic testing, you can ask your child's doctor for a referral to a medical geneticist. After conducting a detailed family history and physical exam of your child, the doctor may recommend genetic testing, which usually is a blood test and sometimes a urine test. If a genetic cause is found, you can determine if the mutation was inherited from one, both or neither parent.\nRead more:\nhttps://iancommunity.org/autism-faq\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Can we tell which side of the family the autism came from?",
        "Answer": "If your child has autism and you are interested in genetic testing, you can ask your child's doctor for a referral to a medical geneticist. After conducting a detailed family history and physical exam of your child, the doctor may recommend genetic testing, which usually is a blood test and sometimes a urine test. If a genetic cause is found, you can determine if the mutation was inherited from one, both or neither parent.\nRead more:\nhttps://iancommunity.org/autism-faq\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How can I help in the search for better treatments for ASD?",
        "Answer": "In order for autism research to advance, participation from individuals with autism and their families is sorely needed. If someone in your family has autism, you can visit (http://www.ianresearch.org) and join the autism research community now. Your family can participate in online studies and also receive notices about local, regional and national studies looking for families like yours.\nRead more:\nhttps://iancommunity.org/autism-faq\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How do I get special education services for my autistic child?",
        "Answer": "For children younger than 3 years old, there are early intervention programs. For children over 3 years of age, there are pre-school and school programs available. Parents should contact their local school district for information on their local programs. In some cases a separate program for special-needs children may be best, but for higher-functioning children integration into a regular school setting may be more appropriate, provided that there is enough support (a part or full-time aide, or other accommodations as needed). It is important that parents work with their child's teacher on an Individual Education Plan (IEP), which outlines in great detail the child's educational program.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/advice-for-parents/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How does ASD affect a person during their life?",
        "Answer": "ASD is a lifelong condition. Most individuals will require varying degrees of support throughout their lives. The supports are unique to the needs and age of the individual. Using evidence based interventions and supports are important to ensure the success of the programs as these interventions have been researched and have shown positive outcomes. \nRead more:\nhttps://www.autismsa.org.au/frequently-asked-questions-about-asd\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "I suspect my child has ASD, what should I do next?",
        "Answer": "When autism spectrum disorder (ASD) is suspected, your child will need a full assessment or evaluation and should be referred for intervention. Autism may be associated with a known genetic syndrome or medical condition. Laboratory tests may be indicated to evaluate for other possible medical conditions that could cause ASD symptoms based on the child's history and physical examination.\nRead more:\nhttps://rockmelon.com/about-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "If Autism is Suspected, What's Next?",
        "Answer": "When autism spectrum disorder (ASD) is suspected, your child will need a full assessment or evaluation and should be referred for intervention. Autism may be associated with a known genetic syndrome or medical condition. Laboratory tests may be indicated to evaluate for other possible medical conditions that could cause ASD symptoms based on the child's history and physical examination.\nRead more:\nhttps://rockmelon.com/about-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Is it possible that more than one person in the family has a form of ASD?",
        "Answer": "Studies are increasingly pointing to a genetic basis for ASD. We are seeing multiple occurrences of the disorder in the same generation or across generations in families, with varying degrees of severity. If you know or suspect there is a history of ASD or other similar symptoms in the family, this is useful information for the diagnostician to know. \nRead more:\nhttps://www.autismontario.com/sites/default/files/2020-04/Getting%20a%20Diagnosis%20of%20ASD_0.pdf\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Is there a relationship between autism and encephalopathy?",
        "Answer": "Most children with an autism spectrum disorder do not and have not had an encephalopathy. Some children with an autism spectrum disorder have had regression and some have had a regressive encephalopathy.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.cdc.gov/ncbddd/autism/topics.html\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What will my autistic child's future be like?",
        "Answer": "The truth is, we don't really know how life will unfold for your childbut there aren't any parents who can know what life holds for their children. We do know that with early intervention, occupational therapy, and other adjustments, parents can increase their child's success and fulfillment in life.\nRead more:\nhttps://springbrookbehavioral.com/frequently-asked-questions-about-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What can I do to prepare my austistic child for the future?",
        "Answer": "The truth is, we don't really know how life will unfold for your childbut there aren't any parents who can know what life holds for their children. We do know that with early intervention, occupational therapy, and other adjustments, parents can increase their child's success and fulfillment in life.\nRead more:\nhttps://springbrookbehavioral.com/frequently-asked-questions-about-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What Can I Do To Prepare My Child For The Future?",
        "Answer": "The truth is, we don't really know how life will unfold for your childbut there aren't any parents who can know what life holds for their children. We do know that with early intervention, occupational therapy, and other adjustments, parents can increase their child's success and fulfillment in life.\nRead more:\nhttps://springbrookbehavioral.com/frequently-asked-questions-about-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Hwo to prepare for the Future?",
        "Answer": "The truth is, we don't really know how life will unfold for your childbut there aren't any parents who can know what life holds for their children. We do know that with early intervention, occupational therapy, and other adjustments, parents can increase their child's success and fulfillment in life.\nRead more:\nhttps://springbrookbehavioral.com/frequently-asked-questions-about-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are some of the symptoms of Autism a Parent should look out for?",
        "Answer": "While autism can only be diagnosed by a healthcare professional, this list of common symptoms\nassociated with autism can help parents and caregivers know what to watch for. \n1) Communication and Social Symptoms   like Pragmatic Language \n2) Behavioral Symptoms  like Repetitive Behaviors \n3)  Difficulty in maintaining eye Contact and Nonverbal Communication \n4) Ritualistic Behaviors like eating same meals everytime\n5) Self-Injury \nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/symptoms-of-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are some tips for parenting kids with autism?",
        "Answer": "1 ) Children with ASD can be impulsive and typically wander or bolt from a safe setting to get to something of interest, such as water so Secure your home.\n2) Work on communication and behavior strategies. Teaching your child strategies to self-calm when stressed and appropriately respond to \"no\" can make a big difference.\n3) Many children with ASD may have sleep problems. If your child is having problems going to sleep or staying asleep, talk to your pediatrician for further evaluation and treatment.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.healthychildren.org/English/health-issues/conditions/Autism/Pages/default.aspx\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What can parents do to help their child with an autism spectrum disorder?",
        "Answer": "Parents have an essential role in providing support to a child with an autism spectrum disorder. They can help to ensure access to health services and education, and offer nurturing and stimulating environments as their child grows up. Recently, it has been shown that parents can also help deliver psychosocial and behavioural treatments to their own children.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.who.int/news-room/q-a-detail/autism-spectrum-disorders-(asd)\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How can I help my child with autism?",
        "Answer": "Parents have an essential role in providing support to a child with an autism spectrum disorder. They can help to ensure access to health services and education, and offer nurturing and stimulating environments as their child grows up. Recently, it has been shown that parents can also help deliver psychosocial and behavioural treatments to their own children.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.who.int/news-room/q-a-detail/autism-spectrum-disorders-(asd)\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "If my child has ASD, what should I do next?",
        "Answer": "1) Attend one or more parent support groups, or join a parent email listserve: Parents can be a wonderful source of support and information.\n2)  Contact your state's Developmental Disabilities program and apply for services\n3)  Contact your local school district and ask about school programs. See what they have to offer.\n4) Having a child with autism can result in many challenges, and you need to be prepared for the long term\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/is-it-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Why do children with autism have difficulty learning in a regular classroom setting?",
        "Answer": "There are many reasons that a child diagnosed with autism spectrum disorders is not able to \nlearn in a regular classroom setting. These include but are not limited to the following reasons:\n 1. coexisting learning disabilities. \n 2. coexisting intellectual disability. \n 3. speech and communication delays. \n 4. aggression to self or others. \n 5. affective Instability. \n 6. require individual supervision to participate in the classroom. \n 7. social reciprocity problems. \nRead more:\nhttps://www.aacap.org/AACAP/Families_and_Youth/Resource_Centers/Autism_Resource_Center/FAQ.aspx\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Are computers useful in the education of an autistic child?",
        "Answer": "Computer-aided education has a significant potential in terms of increasing the educational experiences and facilitating the education\nof the children with special needs. Computers allow adjustment of learning periods for different skills; practising of already learnt skills and\ndeveloping towards the next stage. Moreover, special education teachers and experts emphasize strongly that the computers affect the attitude of the children towards the class activities in a positive way and it provides the children with more opportunity to practise their basic skills.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.ejmste.com/download/importance-of-computer-aided-education-for-children-with-autism-spectrum-disorder-asd-4919.pdf\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Do siblings suffer increased stress as a result of having an autistic brother or sister?",
        "Answer": "Not all siblings will experience these stressful issues, but here are some to be aware of:\n1. Embarrassment around peers; jealousy regarding amount of time parents spend with their brother/sister.\n2. Frustration over not being able to engage or get a response from their brother/sister.\n3. Being the target of aggressive behaviors.\n4. Concern regarding their parents' stress and grief\n5.Concern over their role in future caregiving\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism-society.org/living-with-autism/autism-and-your-family/siblings/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are some ways that parents or family members can deal with the stress?",
        "Answer": "1. Stress is a normal part of life, but families with autistic children often have a lot of stress. For stress management, try making time for family activities, doing positive thinking and relaxation exercises, getting organised and more.\n2.If you or other family members feel very stressed every day, talk to a health professionals.\nRead more:\nhttps://raisingchildren.net.au/autism/communicating-relationships/family-relationships/family-stress-asd\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is facilitated communication?",
        "Answer": "Facilitated communication is a technique that involves a facilitator physically supporting the hand, wrist or arm of an autistic person while the person spells out words on a keyboard or similar device. It's sometimes called 'assisted typing' or 'supported typing'. Facilitated communication is sometimes used with people who have little or no speech, including autistic people.\nRead more:\nhttps://raisingchildren.net.au/autism/therapies-guide/facilitated-communication\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Getting (and keeping) my child dressed is very difficult. What can I do to make it easier?",
        "Answer": "Little changes can make a big difference in limiting your child's frustration while dressing.Check out tips to make getting dressed, putting on socks and shoes, and fastening buttons easier from this resource.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.performancehealth.com/articles/how-to-teach-your-child-with-special-needs-to-dress-independently\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How are parents with Autistic Children stressed?",
        "Answer": "Most parents experience stress, but for those raising children with autism, everyday life often brings Stress with a capital S. They need to keep their child from  running away, manage meltdowns, wrangle with teachers about special education needs, avoid sights or sounds that overload his senses, and drive to therapists or doctors.They do all this while sleep-deprived.Many children with autism simply don't sleep well, so neither do mom and dad.\nRead more:\nhttps://iancommunity.org/ssc/stress-and-autism-parent\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How can I tell if my family needs respite care services?",
        "Answer": "If you notice any of these signs in yourself, or in a family member who is a caregiver, it may be time to consider respite care.\n1. Declining Health or Injury\n2.Becoming Irritable or Impatient\n3.Exhibiting Depression\n4.Making Mistakes\n5.Missing Out on Life\nRead more:\nhttps://www.eddyseniorliving.com/respite-care/5-signs-you-or-a-caregiver-you-know-needs-respite-care/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How do I make my home safe for my autistic child?",
        "Answer": "Here are some tips to improve safety in home \n1. Use Locks and alarms where appropriate\n2. Arrange the furniture appropriately\n3. Make electrical outlets and appliances safe\n4. Safeguard Your Windows\n5. Lock harazdous items away\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism-society.org/living-with-autism/how-the-autism-society-can-help/safe-and-sound/safety-in-the-home/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "I spent time and money childproofing my home when my son was an infant. Do I have to change anything now that he has been diagnosed as autistic?",
        "Answer": "Here are some tips to improve safety in home \n1. Use Locks and alarms where appropriate\n2. Arrange the furniture appropriately\n3. Make electrical outlets and appliances safe\n4. Safeguard Your Windows\n5. Lock harazdous items away\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism-society.org/living-with-autism/how-the-autism-society-can-help/safe-and-sound/safety-in-the-home/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Is my home unsafe for my autistic child?",
        "Answer": "Here are some tips to improve safety in home \n1. Use Locks and alarms where appropriate\n2. Arrange the furniture appropriately\n3. Make electrical outlets and appliances safe\n4. Safeguard Your Windows\n5. Lock harazdous items away\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism-society.org/living-with-autism/how-the-autism-society-can-help/safe-and-sound/safety-in-the-home/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How to make my home safe for my autistic child?",
        "Answer": "Here are some tips to improve safety in home \n1. Use Locks and alarms where appropriate\n2. Arrange the furniture appropriately\n3. Make electrical outlets and appliances safe\n4. Safeguard Your Windows\n5. Lock harazdous items away\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism-society.org/living-with-autism/how-the-autism-society-can-help/safe-and-sound/safety-in-the-home/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "I want to care for my child after I'm gone, but I was told by my lawyer not to leave any money in my child's name. Why?",
        "Answer": "Because showing more than $2,000 in assets could make your child ineligible for federal benefits such as Medicaid and SSI.\nRead more:\nhttps://kidshealth.org/en/parents/needs-planning.html\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Now that I have a trust, who should I choose to be trustee?",
        "Answer": "A family member or friend plus a professional trustee, such as a bank or a lawyer, who can choose the investments and manage the taxes. It is important to pick trustees who will be able to manage the trust for decades.\nRead more:\nhttps://tacanow.org/family-resources/legal-planning-special-needs-trusts/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Why does a parent with an autistic child need a will?",
        "Answer": "A will specifies what will be done with your assets after your death. By writing a will, you make sure that your assets are left to the special needs trust and not to your child. Without a will, a probate court judge could name your child as a beneficiary, which could make your child ineligible for federal benefits. The will is also where you can specify a guardian who will take care of your child.\nRead more:\nhttps://kidshealth.org/en/parents/needs-planning.html\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is a multidisciplinary team and how do they help to diagnose an autistic child?",
        "Answer": "Autism is a complex disorder. A comprehensive evaluation requires a multidisciplinary team and may include a psychologist, speech therapist, occupational therapist and other professionals who diagnose children with autism. The team members will conduct a thorough neurological assessment and in-depth cognitive and language testing. After a thorough evaluation, the team usually meets with parents to explain the results of the evaluation and present the diagnosis.\nRead more:\nhttps://shineireland.com/what-is-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is the Picture Exchange Communication System (PECS)?",
        "Answer": "The Picture Exchange Communication System (PECS) is an augmentative and alternative communication (AAC) system that involves the physical exchange of pictures to communicate with another person for the purpose of requesting or commenting. It was originally developed for use with preschool children with autism spectrum disorder and other related developmental disabilities.\nRead more:\nhttps://childdevelopment.com.au/areas-of-concern/using-speech/picture-exchange-communication-systems-pecs/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "When discussing plans for my autistic teenage son, I've heard the term 'transition.'\u009d What does it mean?",
        "Answer": "As Autistic child reaches late teens their entitlement to public education ends as does the security of fedaral mandated services. For many autistic children this is a time of transition from school life to adult life, making it one of the most challenging times for individuals with ASD and their families. This doesnt come as a surprise because as part of IEP parents should start preparing transition plans  4 or more years before this.\nRead more:\nhttps://books.google.co.in/books?id=LtqUAChbC98C&pg=PA180&lpg=PA180&dq=Autism+When+discussing+plans+for+my+teenage+son,+I%E2%80%99ve+heard+the+term+%E2%80%9Ctransition.%E2%80%9D+What+does+it+mean?&source=bl&ots=vEBPTwDTsA&sig=ACfU3U3kxtUTNOWNuypGWRA9ri05BRBLkQ&hl=en&sa=X&ved=2ahUKEwjjxpPhsuXyAhWbIbcAHaTnA3YQ6AF6BAgwEAM#v=onepage&q=Autism%20When%20discussing%20plans%20for%20my%20teenage%20son%2C%20I%E2%80%99ve%20heard%20the%20term%20%E2%80%9Ctransition.%E2%80%9D%20What%20does%20it%20mean%3F&f=false\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What can I do if I don't agree with the findings in the IEP?",
        "Answer": "If the parents do not agree with the IEP and placement, they may discuss  their concerns with other members of the IEP team and try to work out an agreement. If they still disagree, parents can ask for mediation, or the school may offer mediation. Parents may file a complaint with the state education agency and may request a due process hearing, at which time mediation must be available.\nRead more:\nhttps://www2.ed.gov/parents/needs/speced/iepguide/index.html\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What can a 'special-needs trust'\u009d pay for?",
        "Answer": "These trusts typically pay for things like education, recreation, counseling, and medical attention beyond the simple necessities of life.\nRead more:\nhttps://specialneedsanswers.com/what-can-a-special-needs-trust-pay-for-17061\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Where can I find coping and support?",
        "Answer": "Raising a child with ASD can be physically exhausting and emotionally draining. These suggestions may help:\n1. Find a team of trusted professionals. A team, coordinated by your doctor, may include social workers, teachers, therapists, and a case manager or service coordinator\n2. Take time for yourself and other family members. Caring for a child with autism spectrum disorder can put stress on your personal relationships and your family.\n3.Seek out other families of children with autism spectrum disorder. Other families struggling with the challenges of autism spectrum disorder may have useful advice.\n4.Ask your doctor about new technologies and therapies. Researchers continue to explore new approaches to help children with autism spectrum disorder.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/autism-spectrum-disorder/diagnosis-treatment/drc-20352934\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How to develope friendships with autistic child?",
        "Answer": "One of the best ways to develop friendships is through shared interests such as boy scouts, robotics clubs, school plays, band, school newspaper. Those activities provide peers with whom a child can share his or her favorite interests. Friendships can be encouraged informally by inviting other children to the home to play, with parents or therapists helping to supervise and support those playgroups. In school, recess can be a valuable time for teachers to encourage play with other children. Supervision is important.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/advice-for-parents/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How Can I Deal With the autisim diagnosis?",
        "Answer": "Start by being patient and kind with yourself, your spouse, and your child. Give yourself time to process all of the feelings that you are going to encounter, and don't suppress your emotions. Many parents of children with autism find it helpful to talk to a counselor or therapist after they receive the initial diagnosis. Next, get to work and arm yourself with information. Be sure to reach out to the community to find out about the best programs and other resources in your area.\nRead more:\nhttps://springbrookbehavioral.com/frequently-asked-questions-about-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How can I help my children form a relationship with their autistic sibling?",
        "Answer": "1. Invite the sibling to office visits together with their brother or sister. Let them know how glad you are that they're able to attend the visit, and empower them with the sense that they, too, have a voice in the care of their sibling.\n2.Let them know that negative and confusing thoughts about their sibling with autism are common. tell them that some siblings are resentful of the time parents spend with the child with a disability or illness. Some feel embarrassed by the behavior of their brothers or sisters, while others might even be scared that one day they'll have to care for their sibling.\n3.Parents [should communicate] to their children that they [understand] what they're going through is tough, and that negative feelings are normal. Set aside time for open communication and ventilation of those feelings.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.healthline.com/health/our-two-cents-doctors-answer-questions-about-autism\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How do individuals with austism communicate?",
        "Answer": "Individuals with ASD vary greatly in their communication skills\n1.Some individuals are highly articulate and effective communicators, often well above their chronological age.\n2.Some individuals may never develop language. Others may develop simple language or some may not develop speech but may communicate with devices, signing, pictures or writing\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autismsa.org.au/frequently-asked-questions-about-asd\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Mothers were originally blamed for their child's autism. True or false?",
        "Answer": "True.In the past mothers were blamed for their child's autism. Women were called \"refrigerator mothers\" and accused of being to emotionally frigid with their children, causing the autism. This caused many mothers to feel guilty and doubt their parenting skills. Fortunately, this theory of parenting causing autism has been widely discredited.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.emedicinehealth.com/autism_spectrum_disorder_quiz_iq/faq.htm\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Is there a relationship between mitochondrial disease and autism?",
        "Answer": "A child with autism may or may not have a mitochondrial disease. When a child has both autism and a mitochondrial disease, they sometimes have other problems as well, including epilepsy, problems with muscle tone, and/or movement disorders. More research is needed to find out how common it is for people to have autism and a mitochondrial disorder. Right now, it seems rare.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.cdc.gov/ncbddd/autism/topics.html\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What do we know about the relationship between mitochondrial disease and other disorders related to the brain?",
        "Answer": "Different parts of the brain have different functions. The area of the brain that is damaged by a mitochondrial disease determines how the person is impacted. This means that a person could have seizures; trouble talking or interacting with people; difficulty eating; muscle weakness, or other problems. They could have one issue or several.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.cdc.gov/ncbddd/autism/topics.html\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are the benefits of an Asperger syndrome diagnosis?",
        "Answer": "Some people see a formal diagnosis as an unhelpful label, but for many, getting a thorough assessment and diagnosis may be helpful because it helps people with Asperger syndrome (and their families, partners, employers, colleagues, teachers and friends) to understand why they may experience certain difficulties and what they can do about themit allows people to access services and support.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org.uk/advice-and-guidance/what-is-autism/asperger-syndrome\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What can I do because my autistic child never listens and I seem to be always nagging?",
        "Answer": "Secret signals are a favorite intervention tool that can be used for many situations. The child is taught a signal as a prompt for a desired behavior. For children who speak too loudly indoors or in public, a 'V' sign standing for 'voice' can be made. For sucking thumbs, nail-biting, or even hair pulling, a child can be shown 'three fingers,' as a sign to count to three and take three breaths. And for children who touch themselves inappropriately in public, showing them a 'P' for 'private' can be used to encourage the child to stop and think about what they're doing.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.healthline.com/health/our-two-cents-doctors-answer-questions-about-autism\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is the difference between autism and learning disabilities?",
        "Answer": "Autism and learning disabilities can occur together, however autism spectrum disorder is not a learning disability. Learning disabilities, also referred to as specific learning disorders, are usually identified once a child is in school and are more commonly associated with ADHD (which also can co-occur with autism). They refer to serious and ongoing problems in one of three areas: reading, writing and mathematics. A well-known learning disorder is dyslexia, which affects reading and spelling and often runs in families.\nRead more:\nhttps://rockmelon.com/about-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What other healthcare services are available for my autistic child?",
        "Answer": "Most countries have one set of services for children under 3 years old (early intervention), and a second set of services for older children and adults. Typical services for people with autism include respite, habilitation, speech therapy, and occupational therapy. The qualifications for these programs vary between states, but are generally limited to children with significant developmental delays.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/advice-for-parents/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Is autism contagious?",
        "Answer": "Autism is not a contagious condition. Autism is likely caused by a combination of inherited genes and environmental factors that influence how an autistic person's brain developed before or just after they were born. Autism is not transferred by an infection, and one person cannot catch it from another. \nRead more:\nhttps://iancommunity.org/autism-faq\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Is autism a new condition?",
        "Answer": "It is likely that autism has always existed, but it is impossible to prove or disprove this. Certainly, there have been people including some famous and highly talented people throughout history who displayed typically autistic traits. It took many decades for the fields of neurology, psychology, and psychiatry to evolve the modern definition of autism spectrum disorder and agree upon criteria to diagnose ASD. It is only in the past few years that screening for autism has become prevalent.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.myautismteam.com/resources/autism-an-overview\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Is autism permanent?",
        "Answer": "There is some controversy on the topic of whether autism is always permanent. For the majority of people with ASD, it is a lifelong condition.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.myautismteam.com/resources/autism-an-overview\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What to prepare for my appointment?",
        "Answer": "Your child's health care provider will look for developmental problems at regular checkups. Mention any concerns you have during your appointment. If your child shows any signs of autism spectrum disorder, you'll likely be referred to a specialist who treats children with the disorder for an evaluation. Bring a family member or friend with you to the appointment, if possible, to help you remember information and for emotional support.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/autism-spectrum-disorder/diagnosis-treatment/drc-20352934\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "If there is no autism epidemic, why do the autism statistics just keep climbing?",
        "Answer": "More people than ever before are being diagnosed with an ASD. Since there is more than one cause of autism, there may be more than one reason for the increase. A small portion of the increase of autism may be due to improved diagnosis and awareness, but a report from California (King 2009) reveals that this only explains 25% of the increase.The major reason for the increase is certainly due to environmental factors, not genetics, since there is no such thing as a 'genetic epidemic.'\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/advice-for-parents/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Is there an ASD epidemic?",
        "Answer": "More people than ever before are being diagnosed with an ASD. Since there is more than one cause of autism, there may be more than one reason for the increase. A small portion of the increase of autism may be due to improved diagnosis and awareness, but a report from California (King 2009) reveals that this only explains 25% of the increase.The major reason for the increase is certainly due to environmental factors, not genetics, since there is no such thing as a 'genetic epidemic.'\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/advice-for-parents/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is RDI and how can RDI help?",
        "Answer": "Relationship Development Intervention (RDI) is a method for teaching children how to develop relationships, first with their parents and later with their peers. It directly addresses a core issue in autism, namely the development of social skills and friendships. It involves extensive training of the  parents by a certified RDI consultant, so that they become much more able to effectively interact with their children.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/advice-for-parents/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are the Autism Spectrum Disorders (ASD)?",
        "Answer": "Autism spectrum disorder (ASD) is a neurodevelopmental disorder defined by persistent deficits in social communication and social interaction, accompanied by restricted, repetitive patterns of behavior, interests, or activities. The signs of ASD are usually evident in early childhood. Though it is still considered a lifelong diagnosis, with appropriate early intervention, individuals with ASD can lead  productive, inclusive, and fulfilling lives.\nRead more:\nhttps://autismnavigator.com/what-is-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Are antipsychotic medications helpful in the treatment of autism?",
        "Answer": "Atypical antipsychotics have become indispensable in the treatment of a variety of symptoms in autism. They are frequently used to treat irritability and associated behaviors including aggression and self injury. They may also be efficacious for hyperactivity and stereotyped behavior.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2171144/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How do I change my autistic child's behaviors to reduce risk of accident or injury?",
        "Answer": "Behavioural skills training (BST) is a strategy commonly used to teach a variety of skills to people with disabilities. This can include safety skills such as learning how to solicit help, what to do upon finding a firearm and reducing the risks of abduction. The model involves: (1) instructions, (2) modelling, (3) rehearsal and (4) feedback.\nRead more:\nhttps://theconversation.com/how-parents-and-caregivers-can-help-keep-children-with-autism-safe-120653\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How will I know if a new therapy is right from my autistic child?",
        "Answer": "Four tips to evaluate if your autism therapy is helping your ASD child\n1)Enjoyment level. Children with ASD did much better learning when their therapy included favourite subjects, objects or activities.\n2)Are your children actually learning tools? Or are they performing 'tricks' to make their therapists or you happy.\n3)Does the therapy involve a lot of emotional stress and confusion? This is likely not going to produce lasting results.\n4) Listen to your child and trust your own instincts.\nRead more:\nhttps://autismawarenesscentre.com/what-therapy-good-asd/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Is there any harm in trying unproven treatments on my child?",
        "Answer": "According to the Food and Drug Administration (FDA), products or treatments claiming to cure autism are deceptive and misleading, because there is no cure for autism. The same is true of many products claiming to 'treat' autism or autism-related symptoms. Some may carry significant health risks.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.fda.gov/consumers/consumer-updates/be-aware-potentially-dangerous-products-and-therapies-claim-treat-autism\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Is there anything I should do before giving my child a medication?",
        "Answer": "Before deciding whether medication is right for your child, it's important to talk with your child's doctor about what the medication does and what its side effects are.\nRead more:\nhttps://raisingchildren.net.au/autism/therapies-services/therapies-interventions/medications-asd\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are some common dietary interventions used to treat Autism?",
        "Answer": "Many parents have reported a reduction in autism symptoms when certain dietary interventions have been tried. These diets include the following:\n- Casein-free diet (casein is a protein found in milk; this diet eliminates milk and all by-products of milk)\n- Gluten-free diet (gluten is a protein found in many grains; this diet eliminates such grains)\n- Feingold diet (eliminates additives and chemicals)\n- Specific Carbohydrate diet (removes specific carbohydrates including all grains, lactose and sucrose)\n- Yeast-free Diet (eliminates yeast and sugar)\nRead more:\nhttps://iancommunity.org/cs/what_do_we_know/special_diets\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is Sensory Integration therapy?",
        "Answer": "Sensory integration therapy aims to help kids with sensory processing issues (which some people may refer to as 'sensory integration disorder') by exposing them to sensory stimulation in a structured, repetitive way. The theory behind it is that over time, the brain will adapt and allow kids to process and react to sensations more efficiently.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.understood.org/articles/en/sensory-integration-therapy-what-you-need-to-know\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is TEACCH?",
        "Answer": "During the late 1970's, the Treatment and Education of Autistic and Communication Handicapped Children (TEACCH) research program was formed at the University of North Carolina. The TEACCH method was developed by researchers who wanted a more effective and integrated approach to helping individuals with autism spectrum disorders (ASD). TEACCH is an evidence-based academic program that is based on the idea that autistic individuals are visual learners, so teachers must correspondingly adapt their teaching style and intervention strategies.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.appliedbehavioranalysisprograms.com/faq/what-is-the-teacch-method/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is chelation therapy?",
        "Answer": "Chelation therapy uses special drugs that bind to metals in your blood. You get the chelating medicine through an intravenous (IV) tube in your arm. It's also available in pill form. Once the drug has attached to the metal, your body removes them both through your urine. The American Academy of Pediatrics (AAP) says there's no evidence that chelation is an effective treatment for autism, and it may be dangerous. The AAP doesn't recommend using chelation therapy for autism, except in a clinical trial.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.webmd.com/balance/guide/what-is-chelation-therapy\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Are there therapies or medication treatments for autism?",
        "Answer": "The primary and first-line treatments include intensive behavioral and educational therapies that promote the development of the unique social and communication deficits seen in individuals with autism. Specific interventions should be tailored to each individual's needs and may include both behavioral and pharmacological interventions. Many children benefit from a multidisciplinary team that may include applied behavior analysis (ABA) therapists, speech and language pathologists, occupational therapists, physical therapists and other professionals. There is currently no cure for autism.\nRead more:\nhttps://icahn.mssm.edu/research/seaver/resources/autism-faqs\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Are there medication treatments for autism?",
        "Answer": "The primary and first-line treatments include intensive behavioral and educational therapies that promote the development of the unique social and communication deficits seen in individuals with autism. Specific interventions should be tailored to each individual's needs and may include both behavioral and pharmacological interventions. Many children benefit from a multidisciplinary team that may include applied behavior analysis (ABA) therapists, speech and language pathologists, occupational therapists, physical therapists and other professionals. There is currently no cure for autism.\nRead more:\nhttps://icahn.mssm.edu/research/seaver/resources/autism-faqs\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are the treatments for autism?",
        "Answer": "The primary and first-line treatments include intensive behavioral and educational therapies that promote the development of the unique social and communication deficits seen in individuals with autism. Specific interventions should be tailored to each individual's needs and may include both behavioral and pharmacological interventions. Many children benefit from a multidisciplinary team that may include applied behavior analysis (ABA) therapists, speech and language pathologists, occupational therapists, physical therapists and other professionals. There is currently no cure for autism.\nRead more:\nhttps://icahn.mssm.edu/research/seaver/resources/autism-faqs\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What therapies are available for ASD?",
        "Answer": "The primary and first-line treatments include intensive behavioral and educational therapies that promote the development of the unique social and communication deficits seen in individuals with autism. Specific interventions should be tailored to each individual's needs and may include both behavioral and pharmacological interventions. Many children benefit from a multidisciplinary team that may include applied behavior analysis (ABA) therapists, speech and language pathologists, occupational therapists, physical therapists and other professionals. There is currently no cure for autism.\nRead more:\nhttps://icahn.mssm.edu/research/seaver/resources/autism-faqs\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What kind of support needs are required for people with ASD?",
        "Answer": "Autistic people with complex support needs are people whose support needs span multiple domains (i.e. health, mental health, justice etc). Complex support needs may be indicated by the presence of multiple disabilities, coexisting mental health issues that are persistent and or chronic health conditions.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.amaze.org.au/understand-autism/about-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Can I wait to have my child tested for Autism?",
        "Answer": "There are scientifically validated tests, such as the M-CHAT, that can be used to screen for autism in children as young as 15-18 months. What screening tests do is point to social problems that should be investigated by a health professional, such as a paediatrician or child psychologist. The earlier a child receives a diagnosis the better, as it means they can start on early intervention to help address their social and behavioural challenges.\nRead more:\nhttps://rockmelon.com/about-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Is there a cure for autism?",
        "Answer": "There is no cure for autism. However, early intervention programs have been proven effective at helping autistic children develop skills and improve abilities. \nRead more:\nhttps://www.myautismteam.com/resources/autism-an-overview\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Can My Child's Autism Be Cured?",
        "Answer": "There is no cure for autism. However, early intervention programs have been proven effective at helping autistic children develop skills and improve abilities. \nRead more:\nhttps://www.myautismteam.com/resources/autism-an-overview\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Can vaccines cause ASD?",
        "Answer": "Many studies that have looked at whether there is a relationship between vaccines and autism spectrum disorder (ASD). To date, the studies continue to show that vaccines are not associated with ASD.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.cdc.gov/ncbddd/autism/topics.html\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Do vaccines cause autism spectrum disorder (ASD)?",
        "Answer": "Many studies that have looked at whether there is a relationship between vaccines and autism spectrum disorder (ASD). To date, the studies continue to show that vaccines are not associated with ASD.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.cdc.gov/ncbddd/autism/topics.html\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Does ABA always work for ASD?",
        "Answer": "Though ABA has been shown to be effective, many of the aspects of applying the principles of behavior analysis in the treatment of autism have not been investigated thoroughly. For example, how many hours per week are necessary to produce a change is not known. It is, however, quite likely that the proficiency of the providers of service, both direct care therapists or teachers and their supervisors will play a significant rol e in the progress that any child makes.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.necc.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/AutismFAQ.pdf\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Does mercury used in vaccines cause autism?",
        "Answer": "Massive systemic damage can occur through excessive methylmercury exposure. The Food and Drug Administration has advised pregnant women, nursing mothers, and young children limit their intake of certain types of fish, like tuna, that tend to contain high levels of methylmercury in order to prevent excessive methylmercury consumption. Thimerosal consists of 49% ethylmercury. The most definitive study to date was conducted by Danish researchers (Hviid et al., 2003). It looked at thousands of children who received either vaccines containing thimerosal or vaccines without this preservative and found that the rates o f autism were identical in the two groups.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.necc.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/AutismFAQ.pdf\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How Pediatricians Screen for Autism",
        "Answer": "Your child's pediatric primary health care provider will start screening your baby for signs of developmental or communication challenges. They observe how your baby giggles, looks to you\u00c2\u00a0for reassurance, tries to regain your\u00c2\u00a0attention during a\u00c2\u00a0conversation, points or waves, responds to his or her\u00c2\u00a0name, and\u00c2\u00a0cries.\u00c2\u00a0It is those observations in combination with\u00c2\u00a0family history, health examinations, and parents' perspectives that help pediatric primary health care providers identify children at risk for ASD.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.healthychildren.org/English/health-issues/conditions/Autism/Pages/default.aspx\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How can I find the best treatments for myself or my autistic child?",
        "Answer": "Research suggests that early intensive behavioral intervention, based on applied behavioral analysis, is effective at improving language, function and behavior in individuals with autism. There are two drugs, risperidone and aripiprazole, that can improve challenging behaviors such as emotional distress, aggression, hyperactivity and self-injury, but these drugs do not lead to improvements in social skills or communication. Interventions focused on parent training and cognitive behavioral therapy\u00c2\u00a0can improve social skills, communication, language use and management of challenging behaviors.\nRead more:\nhttps://iancommunity.org/autism-faq\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "I have just been diagnosed. What's next?",
        "Answer": "When anyone is diagnosed, the most important next step is for professionals and family members involved with the person to learn about the methods of support and intervention used with individuals with ASD and apply them to their interactions with this person. Local agencies specializing in developmental disabilities in general or ASD in particular, and resources on the Internet, are excellent places to look for this information. The diagnosis will also allow parents of adults to find support groups with those in similar situations.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autismontario.com/sites/default/files/2020-04/Getting%20a%20Diagnosis%20of%20ASD_0.pdf\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "I think I/my child may have autism but I'm not sure. How can I find out?",
        "Answer": "The first step is a conversation with your child's pediatrician. The American Academy of Pediatrics recommends that all children be screened for autism at their 18-month and 24-month well-child checkups. If there are concerns, your pediatrician should refer you to a specialist (such as a child psychiatrist or psychologist, developmental pediatrician, or pediatric neurologist) for a more extensive evaluation.\nRead more:\nhttps://icahn.mssm.edu/research/seaver/resources/autism-faqs\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are some Psychiatric Medications available for ASD?",
        "Answer": "There are no psychiatric medications for 'autism,'\u00c2\u009d but there are many psychiatric medications used for treating specific symptoms often found in autism, such as aggression, self-injury, anxiety, depression, obsessive/compulsive disorders, and attention deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD). These medications generally function by altering the level of neurotransmitters (chemical messengers) in the brain. There is no medical test to determine if a particular medication is called for; the decision is based on the psychiatrist's evaluation of the patient's symptoms.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/advice-for-parents/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Do vaccines cause or worsen mitochondrial diseases?",
        "Answer": "As of now, there are no scientific studies that say vaccines cause or worsen mitochondrial diseases. We do know that certain illnesses that can be prevented by vaccines, such as the flu, can trigger the regression that is related to a mitochondrial disease. More research is needed to determine if there are rare cases where underlying mitochondrial disorders are triggered by anything related to vaccines.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.cdc.gov/ncbddd/autism/topics.html\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Is it true that there are no treatments for autism?",
        "Answer": "While there are no treatments to cure autism or medications to treat core symptoms, there are some medications that can help some people with ASD function better in daily life. \nRead more:\nhttps://www.emedicinehealth.com/autism_spectrum_disorder_quiz_iq/faq.htm\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What treatments can influence prognosis of ASD?",
        "Answer": "Many researchers, clinicians, and parents have investigated and tracked the efficacy of autism treatments over time. While each individual with autism is different, some treatments have shown positive effects for people with autism. Parents should seek out the advice of a qualified health professional before starting any autism treatment.\u00c2\u00a0 Several co-occurring conditions called comorbidities by clinicianshave been identified. Treating underlying conditions and related disorders can improve the prognosis for individuals with autism.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/autism-prognosis/\n \nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are evidence-based therapies?",
        "Answer": "Evidence-based therapy means that there has been some conclusive research to prove the effects of a therapy on its potential users. Whilst many treatments claim to have evidence proving they work, in many cases, there has actually been no extensive top level research done (Autism Awareness Australia, 2018).\nRead more:\nhttps://rockmelon.com/about-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What if I Have Autism?",
        "Answer": "You should consider consulting your doctor for a referral to professionals qualified to make an adult autism diagnosis. Because some people don't receive a diagnosis with some types of autism, for instance Asperger Syndrome, when they are child. Clinical psychologists, neurologists and psychologists can make an autism diagnosis.\nRead more:\nhttps://otsimo.com/en/frequently-asked-questions-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is ASD?",
        "Answer": "ASD is the acronym for 'Autism Spectrum Disorder'. This umbrella term includes autistic disorder (also known as 'classic autism'\u00c2\u009d), Asperger's disorder, and pervasive developmental disorder not otherwise specified (also known as 'atypical autism'\u00c2\u009d) according to the Fourth Edition of the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders (DSM) issued in 1992 (Autism Awareness Australia, 2018).\nRead more:\nhttps://rockmelon.com/about-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is Applied Behavioral Analysis (ABA)?",
        "Answer": "Applied Behavior Analysis or ABA is the application of the empirically validated principles of behavior to build skills through directed instruction and to treat problem behaviors by determining the function of them and arranging for effective intervention that addresses the behavior's function. ABA is an approach to analyzing each individual's skill deficits and problem behaviors. Each child brings with them a distinct set of difficulties. No single treatment package can be used for all children and ABA is a method for examining the needs of each person. Specific instruction can then be tailored to a child's unique situation.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.necc.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/AutismFAQ.pdf\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is Autism?",
        "Answer": "Autism is a neurodevelopmental condition which is usually diagnosed in the first 3 years of life. Generally parents become concerned when their child has delays in speech development, limited social relatedness, and restricted interests and activities. The diagnosis of autism requires disturbances in each of three domains:\n 1. Social relatedness \n 2. lack of developmentally-appropriate make-believe or social play. \n 3. Restricted interests and activities\nRead more:\nhttps://www.aacap.org/AACAP/Families_and_Youth/Resource_Centers/Autism_Resource_Center/FAQ.aspx\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is 'the Spectrum'\u00c3\u201a\u00c2\u009d?",
        "Answer": "Autism is a term that is constantly redefined the more it's studied and it is an umbrella term. Being 'on the spectrum'\u00c2\u009d means having some sort of autism. Subsets of autism ranges from mild to severe. We can say that every case in autism is unique. While some individuals on the autism spectrum have great art skills and above-average intelligence, some have above below-average to average intelligence. Most people on the spectrum can have a distinctive ability resulting from their peculiar way of viewing the world, while others suffering from autism are unable to live without aid.\nRead more:\nhttps://otsimo.com/en/frequently-asked-questions-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "When Not to Worry About Autism?",
        "Answer": "Are we worrying too much?\u00a0Too little?\u00a0What is enough of a reason\u00a0to\u00a0worry?\u00a0Trust your instincts. You know your child best. If you note that your child is not developing like other children or something just seems off, it is important to talk with a trusted source.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.healthychildren.org/English/health-issues/conditions/Autism/Pages/default.aspx\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Should I be worried About Autism?",
        "Answer": "Are we worrying too much?\u00a0Too little?\u00a0What is enough of a reason\u00a0to\u00a0worry?\u00a0Trust your instincts. You know your child best. If you note that your child is not developing like other children or something just seems off, it is important to talk with a trusted source.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.healthychildren.org/English/health-issues/conditions/Autism/Pages/default.aspx\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Who is qualified to diagnose a youth or adult with ASD?",
        "Answer": "Medical doctors (GPs, psychiatrists) and psychologists are permitted to give a formal diagnosis. Social workers, occupational therapists, and speechlanguage pathologists may provide a professional opinion about the likelihood that an individual has the disorder. However, this impression must be confirmed by one of the previously mentioned professionals for this to be a formal diagnosis.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autismontario.com/sites/default/files/2020-04/Getting%20a%20Diagnosis%20of%20ASD_0.pdf\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Who is qualified to provide ABA services?",
        "Answer": "The person who supervises the implementation of an ABA program should be a \"behavior analyst.\" There is a Behavior Analyst Certification Board \u00c2\u00ae (BACB \u00c2\u00ae) and the criteria for becoming a Board Certified Behavior Analyst \u00c2\u00ae or BCBA \u00c2\u00ae are listed at www.bacb.com.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.necc.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/AutismFAQ.pdf\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Why ABA?",
        "Answer": "No single \"treatment package\" will serve every child's needs and no individual can claim to own ABA. ABA is the application of the principles of learning to 1) build skills and 2) treat problem behavior. It works because each person's behavior is assessed to determine what skills they have not mastered and what types of problem behavior interfere with learning and social functioning. For skill deficits, direct instruction is provided until the skill is mastered. For problem behavior, specific analysis of why the behavior occurs is used to develop treatment to eliminate the behavior or teach the person to use other more appropriate behavior to serve the same function.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.necc.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/AutismFAQ.pdf\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Will My autistic Child Ever Be Able To Talk?",
        "Answer": "There is no way to know. Some children with autism develop language skills later in life and others never do. However, we do know that there are ways parents can still communicate with nonverbal children, and that there are fewer children with autism who are minimally verbal and nonverbal than there used to be, partly due to earlier detection, earlier intervention, and behaviorally-based treatments and therapies like Applied Behavior Analysis.\nRead more:\nhttps://springbrookbehavioral.com/frequently-asked-questions-about-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Will My autistic Child Ever Be Normal?",
        "Answer": "There's a saying in the autism community that normal is just a setting on your washing machine. On one level, nobody has a normal child. All we really have is a range of what's average when it comes to child development, but that's not much comfort to a parent wondering about developmental delays, meltdowns, lack of language skills, and self-destructive or maladaptive behaviors. While every child with autism is different, with patience, treatment, and professional intervention, even children who are on the more severe end of the autism spectrum can learn and develop positive social skills and other life skills.\nRead more:\nhttps://springbrookbehavioral.com/frequently-asked-questions-about-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Do some families with autistic child deal with stress better than others?",
        "Answer": "Family members experience and respond to stress in different ways. There's no one right way of feeling or responding to your child with autism spectrum disorder (ASD). However, it does help to be understanding of each other's feelings.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.babybonus.msf.gov.sg/parentingresources/web/Special-Needs/Well-Being/Daily_Care/Specialneeds_Family_Stress?_afrLoop=72926125641457770&_afrWindowMode=0&_afrWindowId=null#%40%3F_afrWindowId%3Dnull%26_afrLoop%3D72926125641457770%26_afrWindowMode%3D0%26_adf.ctrl-state%3Dd8wfhcrty_4\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How to talk about autism?",
        "Answer": "Autistic people describe themselves and autism in different ways, so it is always best to ask the individual themselves what their preference is. If you can't ask them, try asking someone who knows them well or use the language they use. There are many terms used to describe autism. These terms are used by autistic people themselves, their supporters and in education, health and social settings. These terms may include:\n- Autistic person\n- Person with autism\n- On the spectrum\n- Autism Spectrum Condition\n- Autism Spectrum Disorder (ASD) \n- Asperger's\nRead more:\nhttps://www.ambitiousaboutautism.org.uk/information-about-autism/understanding-autism/how-to-talk-about-autism\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How do I talk to people with autism?",
        "Answer": "Autistic people describe themselves and autism in different ways, so it is always best to ask the individual themselves what their preference is. If you can't ask them, try asking someone who knows them well or use the language they use. There are many terms used to describe autism. These terms are used by autistic people themselves, their supporters and in education, health and social settings. These terms may include:\n- Autistic person\n- Person with autism\n- On the spectrum\n- Autism Spectrum Condition\n- Autism Spectrum Disorder (ASD) \n- Asperger's\nRead more:\nhttps://www.ambitiousaboutautism.org.uk/information-about-autism/understanding-autism/how-to-talk-about-autism\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are some ways that parents with autistic child can reduce their stress?",
        "Answer": "Avoiding stress when you have a child with autism spectrum disorder:\n- Getting organised.\n- Looking after yourself.\n- Maintaining family traditions.\n- Support from family and friends.\n- Positive thinking and self-talk.\n- Relaxation and breathing strategies.\n- Strategies for challenging behaviour.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.babybonus.msf.gov.sg/parentingresources/web/Special-Needs/Well-Being/Daily_Care/Specialneeds_Family_Stress?_afrLoop=72928617531431760&_afrWindowMode=0&_afrWindowId=null#%40%3F_afrWindowId%3Dnull%26_afrLoop%3D72928617531431760%26_afrWindowMode%3D0%26_adf.ctrl-state%3D1d0e7p7js7_4\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Can My Child with Autism Attend School?",
        "Answer": "Parents often wonder \"is homeschooling a good option for my child with autism?\" Think about this: nationwide, 1 in 59 children are diagnosed with autism. That means that public schools have many students on their rolls who have unique learning needs. Many families who have a child on the autism spectrum explore alternative educational options. Private schools, charter magnets, and homeschooling are options that have worked successfully for students with autism.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.time4learning.com/homeschooling/special-needs/autism/homeschool-vs-public-school.html\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How are people of different degrees of autism understood?",
        "Answer": "Autism is known as a spectrum condition as no two persons diagnosed with autism are the same. They may differ in the interaction of 2 key dimensions:\n- Severity of Autism\n- Intellectual Ability\nAny person with autism may have differing degrees of autism as well as intellectual abilities. This helps us understand that any combination may exist and we must not make assumptions that high autism always implies low ability or vice versa.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org.sg/living-with-autism/what-is-autism\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How does visual perception impact someone with ASD?",
        "Answer": "Individuals with ASD, atypical visual perception can complicate the processing of visually presented social cues, and this may eventually result in isolation from confusing social information. Among other sensory domains, altered visual perception has been widely reported in individuals with ASD.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7350544/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How early can you start treatment for ASD?",
        "Answer": "If autism is caught in infancy, treatment can take full advantage of the young brain's remarkable plasticity. Although autism is hard to diagnose before 24 months, symptoms often surface between 12 and 18 months. If signs are detected by 18 months of age, intensive treatment may help to rewire the brain and reverse the symptoms.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.helpguide.org/articles/autism-learning-disabilities/does-my-child-have-autism.htm#\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are secondary conditions and difficulties associated with ASD?",
        "Answer": "Autism may be present with other conditions. This can affect people in different ways. Some other conditions autistic people commonly experience are:\n- speech and language challenges\n- intellectual disability\n- sleep problems\n- attention problems\n- hyperactivity\n- epilepsy\n- anxiety and depression\n- challenges with fine and gross motor skills.\nThere are other conditions that are associated with autism, including Fragile X Syndrome, Tuberous Sclerosis and other genetic disorders.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.amaze.org.au/understand-autism/about-autism/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are some causes of behavioral change in autistic children?",
        "Answer": "The first of its kind, the Yale study used fMRI scans conducted during an emotion perception task to compare the brain activity of autistic children who do and do not exhibit disruptive behavior. The researchers found reduced connectivity between the amygdala and ventrolateral prefrontal cortex -- a pathway critical to the regulation of emotion -- in the brains of children who exhibit disruptive behavior as compared to the brains of children who do not. This finding points to a brain mechanism of emotion dysregulation in children with autism and offers a potential biomarker for developing targeted treatments for irritability and aggression in autism\nRead more:\nhttps://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2019/04/190418164340.htm\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What can I do about my austistic child's stress?",
        "Answer": "Reducing and managing stress for families with autistic children:\n- Positive thinking and self-talk.\n- Relaxation and breathing strategies.\n- Getting organised.\n- Making time for enjoyable family activities.\n- Maintaining and modifying family traditions and rituals.\n- Support from family and friends.\n- Respite.\nRead more:\nhttps://raisingchildren.net.au/autism/communicating-relationships/family-relationships/family-stress-asd\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "How can I help my autistic child with stress?",
        "Answer": "Reducing and managing stress for families with autistic children:\n- Positive thinking and self-talk.\n- Relaxation and breathing strategies.\n- Getting organised.\n- Making time for enjoyable family activities.\n- Maintaining and modifying family traditions and rituals.\n- Support from family and friends.\n- Respite.\nRead more:\nhttps://raisingchildren.net.au/autism/communicating-relationships/family-relationships/family-stress-asd\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA)?",
        "Answer": "The Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA) ensures that all children with disabilities are entitled to a free appropriate public education to meet their unique needs and prepare them for further education, employment and independent living. Prior to IDEA, over 4 million children with disabilities were denied appropriate access to public education. Many children were denied entry into public school altogether, while others were placed in segregated classrooms, or in regular classrooms without adequate support for their special needs.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.apa.org/advocacy/education/idea\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What medical tests should the doctor perform when making a diagnosis of ASD?",
        "Answer": "Routine medical tests are usually performed by traditional pediatricians, but these exams rarely reveal underlying medical problems that are often associated with autism, such as gastrointestinal problems, nutritional and metabolic deficiencies, toxic metal burden, and immune dysfunction. Unfortunately, many physicians believe, though incorrectly, that the only useful medical treatments are psychiatric medications to reduce seizures and behavioral problems. Genetic testing for Fragile X syndrome can help identify one possible cause, and this testing is typically recommended when there is IDD in the family history. The Autism Research Institute supports an integrative medical approach to treating individuals on the autism spectrum.\nRead more:\nhttps://www.autism.org/advice-for-parents/\n\nContinue asking or input 'go back' to Main Service"
    }
]